"Since our gods and our aspirations
are no longer anything but scientific
why should our loves not be so as well?"
Villiers de L'Isle-Adam "Tomorrow's Eve"
Eye in the Sky 202 to Control.
Now on station above scene.
Opening data link.
Sit-rep?
52 minutes ago the suspect killed its
owner at his condo the first crime scene
...and fled the area.
Suspect is now holed up in the second
crime scene an unmarked alleyway
where it's killed
two officers.
All entrances have been blocked.
In two minutes we plan to go in.
That's a Section 9 cyborg.
When those guys cross your path
you're in for a world of trouble.
Sounds like the Cyber Police
are itching to step in.
They're requesting
a data link.
First Public Security
and now the Cybercops huh?
Politely ask them
to take a hike.
Please help us...
The moon fails to shine down on either day or night
and the night bird calls out in sadness.
When I turn to look
the flowers had all fallen away.
It was as if all comfort...
...had vanished from the world.
As the gods leave...
...to gather in the new world
day breaks and the night bird calls out.
The blossoms beseech the gods.
"Even though in this world..."
"...we may know grief and suffering"
"our dreams shall never die"
...and they fall from the branch in anger.
There have already been eight homicides
committed by gynoids this week.
In each case they self-terminated
after killing their owners
and their cyberbrains
were reformatted.
The units were all made by
the Locus Solus company
...the type 2052
"Hadaly."
They're preliminary betas
of a mass-production model.
Apparently they were provided for free
to the company's contracted evaluators
but all of the units have
now been recalled.
According to the latest report they
submitted to the authorities
no bugs had been detected in either
their hardware or software.
You were paying attention
I hope.
A new line of gynoids went berserk for
reasons unknown and killed their owners.
The manufacturer recalled them
in a panic.
Next will come the usual lawsuits from the
next of kin and then protracted civil trials...
...centering around producer responsibility
to be followed by massive payouts.
I'd say I understand the gist of it except
for why Section 9 is getting involved.
You understand
do you?
More often than not what we call
understanding is based on wishful thinking.
At this time there are two reasons
for Section 9 to get involved.
The first is that no suits have
been filed by the next of kin.
All the cases have been settled in-house
at the manufacturer Locus Solus.
And the second is that among
the victims is a politician
as well as a retired
Public Security official.
It's possible that this might be
an act of terrorism
so determining if we ought to take lead
on the case also falls under our purview.
Ishikawa and Azuma you run down
leads on the victims.
You two check out the
gynoids in question.
No questions.
Get going.
Just so we're straight on this I didn't
ask to be partnered with you.
I'll be the first to admit that I
might not measure up to the Major.
That's not it.
I hear she's still
listed as missing.
The only things she really owned
were her brain and her Ghost.
Of course she herself wasn't too sure
she had even those.
Her prosthetic body and cyberbrain were
just government-issued equipment
and the memories inside that cyberbrain
were government property
top-secret intel
and all.
What the top brass want to get back
is those memories.
They couldn't care less
if she's alive or dead.
So how do you want
to start on this?
Well Locus Solus is a Northern Frontier
manufacturer located way up north.
Let's start with the basics and pay
the local cops' crime lab a visit.
"Police"
You huh?
We're here about that doll the
Big Man here smashed up the other day.
That thing killed two
of our guys.
You don't expect to walk out
of here with it do you?
Part of our investigation is
to make that determination.
Forensics is on the 19th floor
end of the hall on the right.
Do I need to
show you the way?
No thanks. We didn't
come here for a tour.
"Not even crows will peck at a
persimmon that is still green."
But you can be sure they'll be circling
overhead when they're ripe.
Back when you were a cop wouldn't
you have had a few choice words...
...for somebody who swooped in out of
the blue and swiped a case from you?
That's what pissed me off. It's like
I was looking at the old me.
"Don't find fault with the mirror when
it's your own face that's distorted."
"The mirror is not a tool for realizing
the truth but rather for obscuring it" huh?
Hell neither one of you has a face
that I'd wanna see in the mirror.
If I told you once I told you a thousand
times. I'm not doing a joint examination.
Keep pestering me and I'll
have you taken into custody.
I'm Togusa Public Security Section 9.
My scary-looking friend here is...
The one who filled this poor girl
with double-aught buck I take it.
If you'd have used
.50-caliber hollowpoints
it would've been a simple
matter to restore it.
It killed three people.
And two of those were cops.
Before she was shot she tried
to commit suicide. Didn't she?
What do you mean
by "suicide" um...
Haraway.
Miss er Haraway what do you mean
by a robot committing suicide?
The gynoids give themselves authorization
to attack humans...
...by deliberately
malfunctioning.
But as a logical consequence
of those malfunctions
they're also freeing themselves
from Ethics Code article three.
"Protect your own existence so long as such
protection does not harm a human being."
I think it would be more accurate to
call it "self-termination" personally...
Yes if you assume that there is a clear
distinction between man and machine.
Is this "suicide" phenomenon
limited to a particular model?
I wish I could say it is
but no.
These past few years we've been seeing
a spike in robot-related incidents.
It's especially bad
in the "pet" models.
Any idea as to
the cause?
Who knows? Cyberbrain corruption
caused by a virus or microorganism?
Human error during the
manufacturing process?
Degraded functionality due to
age-related deterioration?
Take your pick.
Personally though...
What?
If you ask me I think it's because
humans discard their robots.
You know when they don't
want them anymore.
When the new models come out
people buy the latest and greatest
some of the discarded ones
end up on the streets
...where they gradually deteriorate
from lack of maintenance.
The robots just want us to stop
treating them as disposable.
Oh come on...
Humans and robots
are different.
But that sort of faith is nothing more than
the recognition that humans aren't robots
which is on the same level as
saying that white is not black.
Unlike things like industrial robots
pet androids and gynoids...
...weren't designed with utilitarianism
and pragmatism in mind.
Why did we feel the need to
create them in man's image?
In an idealized image
at that.
Why does humanity go to such lengths
to create these reflections of itself?
Do you have children?
Yes a daughter.
Children have always deviated
from the human norm.
That is if we define a human as something
that has a fixed identity...
...and acts in accordance
to its own free will.
What then are children those early-stage
humans who exist in a state of chaos?
Internally they clearly differ from humanity
yet they have the shape of humans.
The dolls that little girls use
when they play "mommy"...
...aren't merely a surrogate for a child
or something to practice on.
Perhaps these girls aren't practicing
raising children.
Rather perhaps playing with dolls
is much the same as raising children.
What in the world are
you talking about?
In other words child rearing is the quickest
method of realizing that oldest of dreams
...the act of creating
an artificial human.
That's the way
I see it.
Children aren't...
They aren't dolls!
Descartes didn't differentiate between man
and machine organic and inorganic life.
There was a doll that looked just like his
daughter Francine who died at age five.
He named it after her
and lavished it with love.
I almost forgot
about that...
Look can we get back to
the real-world matter at hand?
I'd like to hear your initial opinions
on that robot.
Locus Solus'
type 2052 "Hadaly."
True.
It's a fine piece
of work.
I'm told it's a beta-model mass-production
unit but it's built to unusual specs.
Unusual specs?
It's equipped with organs that aren't
exactly necessary on a maid-type model.
Meaning what
exactly?
It's a sexbot.
It's not a hobby you can brag about
to the public but it's not illegal.
Now I get it. It's no wonder that the
next of kin dropped the lawsuits.
As their cyberbrains shut down
they reformatted.
It's a standard practice to safeguard
the control software's technical data.
However...
"However" what?
There was a file left in the audio buffer.
Shall I play it?
Please help us...
Please help...
Thanks for
all your help.
Hey!
Um would you mind if I asked
a personal question?
I've never given birth to any children
and I haven't raised any.
I'm not registered
at the egg bank either.
Thank you for your time
Miss um...
Just "Haraway."
No Miss or Missus needed.
That lady wasn't your
typical engineer was she?
She's the type who fills out the
"personal comments" column in forms.
I used to do that
a lot too.
That's why you took so long
to climb the ranks.
Anyway I guess we should keep that
gynoid's cyberbrain at the Section 9 lab.
I guess we won't be talking
with that lady again huh?
She the type you like
to hang out with?
Yeah I have a thing for older women.
So what next?
We follow
the playbook.
Talk to the
shipping inspector huh?
09 calling 907. 602 in progress
at a boathouse in sector 201.
Victim is a shipping inspector
at Locus Solus.
Scene secured two minutes
prior to arrival of local police.
907 roger.
Goodness gracious
what a coincidence.
On every spring day between this world
and the next I spur on the coach.
What's up you're here
by yourself?
Yeah Koga went back to base
with the stiff...
...after getting reacquainted with the
tuna sandwich he had for dinner.
Geez that guy
is pathetic...
The crime scene as of
22 minutes ago.
You made a rookie
carry that back?
Hey everything's a
learning experience.
Okay here's a rundown
of the situation.
Match run on the
vic's cyberbrain.
Jacques Vaucanson Locus Solus
Chief Shipping Inspector. Age 54.
Submitted vacation request five days ago
then dropped off the radar.
Three days ago signed a rental
agreement for this houseboat...
...with a planned stay
of five days.
Murder weapons were kitchen implements
that came with the boat.
Search run on vehicles in the area.
Record of parked criminal vehicle located.
Check for yakuza affiliation
in progress.
Seven cards of various types found in
overcoat believed to belong to victim.
Check for usage
in progress.
Oopsie daisy. Got ourselves a
.38-caliber Smith & Wesson here.
Model 2602.
Looks like he didn't
have time to use it.
That might not have
done him any good.
An illegally amped-up cyborg.
Or a pro pretending to be a psycho.
969 calling 906.
Crime scene ETA 20 seconds.
- Hey don't mess up my...
- We're not touching anything.
Let's let Forensics
take it from here.
907 to 09. Relinquishing
crime scene to 969.
09 acknowledged.
Today's my
daughter's birthday.
A family man huh?
I'll drop you off.
I'm in the opposite direction.
Ishikawa?
I'm the
other way too.
They say a daughter's birthday
takes priority over everything else.
Looks like you guys are
having a grand old time.
Coming out in person huh?
That's a rare sight.
Our stiff was missing some parts
so I decided to get involved.
We'll get outta your hair
so take your time looking for 'em.
Why aren't you letting the
local cops handle this?
The Old Man's got his knickers
in a twist over it for some reason.
Found them! They're sitting
in jars in the refrigerator!
Heart. Liver. Kidneys.
The pancreas too.
This is one
tidy SOB...
Inumaru Foods'
wet dog food huh?
If you bought dry food
it'd keep for six months.
I can't feed her
that garbage.
So I hear you're teamed up
with Togusa.
Better him than some rookie
fresh out of the academy.
He's competent enough for a former
detective. I've got no complaints.
'Cause the only person
you ever partnered with...
...who you thought made the grade
was the Major.
- Look...
- Ishikawa.
I liked you better when
you were the silent type.
Later.
Batou.
Yeah what?
Take my advice.
Switch to the dry.
Just from a nutritional balance
perspective it's the smart choice.
Cause of death was crushing of the
cervical vertebrae by blunt force trauma.
We determined that the kitchen tools
weren't the murder weapon
but were instead used to
mutilate the corpse.
So you're saying that they killed the guy
then leisurely dismantled him?
Yeah that's what it
boils down to.
We confirmed that the organs stored in
the refrigerator belonged to the victim.
They showed early signs of gastritis
and cirrhosis of the liver.
Looks like he had
a drinking problem.
Why'd he gut the guy
so meticulously?
Maybe to make us think he was
mentally unstable or a sicko?
Or to reinforce a message
of punishment or revenge.
Which would nix the "pro hit
disguised as a thrill kill" theory.
What's the story with
the mangled doorknob?
Analysis identified the prosthetic limb
as a Chinese-made NR26.
A Crab Claw huh?
Isn't that military?
They're available on the black market.
A lot of 'em are defective though.
It was also a match to the lacerations
on the corpse's head.
What about the owner of that car
the one with criminal history?
Looks like there were a lot of illegal mods
so tracking it down wasn't...
Just report
your findings.
According to my follow-up investigation on
the records of the neighboring parking lot
the car belongs to the Koujinkai
a designated violent criminal organization.
It's been bulletproofed and the chassis
and rear shocks have been beefed up.
It's been spotted at the scenes of multiple
violent crimes in the past.
Tricked-out wheels for
a tricked-out cyborg.
Yeah for hired muscle with
illegally amped output.
Are we looking at some kind
of yakuza payback here?
The problem is motive.
What do we have on the Koujinkai?
They're a Japanese mob group
that goes way back.
Drugs prostitution human trafficking
Real estate extortion.
They've got a finger
in just about every pie.
A Hadaly ripped their boss Inoue's
head off three days ago.
His deputy Wakabayashi is now
running things in his place.
Come on it's obvious.
Yeah avenging the previous boss
is a prerequisite for taking over.
There's just one problem with that.
If our vic was expecting retaliation
why would he choose a place to lie low
that was inside Koujinkai territory?
His cyberbrain data's been wiped so I
guess we'll have to check out his associates.
In any case this is definitely
a job for the local cops.
And the possibility of it being a terrorist
act disguised as a robot runaway?
At this time we haven't found any
political factors that link all the victims.
That's looking
awfully unlikely.
Batou and Togusa will work full-time
on these Hadaly runaways
including this incident.
The rest of you return to
your regular shifts.
Dismissed.
Togusa.
Come see me
before you leave.
What do you think?
I guess we'll have to check into a link
between the Koujinkai and Locus Solus to...
I was talking about
Batou.
Partners are supposed to monitor
each other's mental state.
Even so I'm not a cyborg
and I'm certainly no cyber-physician.
"To understand Caesar
one need not be Caesar."
You have a family as I recall.
Do you consider yourself happy?
Sure I guess...
A man once said that we are never so
happy or so unhappy as we suppose.
That what is important is to never grow
tired of your life and aspirations.
What are you
getting at sir?
When I look
at him lately
I'm reminded of the Major
just before she disappeared.
"Let a man walk alone
let him commit no sin"
"let him have few wishes
like an elephant in the forest."
Chief. Why did you
choose me for this?
Because it was the Major who
scouted you from the police force.
So what did he
have to say?
Apparently you don't have to
be Caesar to understand him.
That goes
without saying.
The world can't live up to standards
set by the giants of history.
You planning to start a war
or something?
One need not be a yakuza when
one goes to a yakuza office
but you do need to
pack some heat.
Look before we head out I want
to make sure of something.
Yeah what?
We're just going there
to talk right?
Do you hate yakuza?
Can't stand the bastards.
Same here.
We're going there to talk.
Just talk. Right?
Hey didn't I tell you that
to go to a yakuza office...
Yeah you don't have
to become a yakuza.
But you also said that
you needed weapons.
I have a family
got it?
I can go by myself
if you want.
I'm going with you.
That's what partners do.
So I want you to give me
your word.
We're just gonna talk. I'll avoid
shooting as much as possible.
- Happy now?
- Fine.
Then saddle up
partner.
Who the hell
are you two?
We need to talk with your
buddy Wakabayashi. Go get him.
You said you were gonna
avoid shooting.
I did avoid shooting.
As much as possible.
Get moving point man.
Reinforcements are on the way.
A hologram?
The son of a bitch
hacked our eyes?!
Blame those cheap-ass
cyberbrains of yours.
What's the holdup?
It's a dark narrow stairwell.
How do we handle this?
One at a time.
I'll go first.
I'll go first. You're so big that
I won't be able to cover you.
I set off your little presents
above our heads.
Even assuming they'd gone off in
their maximum effective radius
it'd take more than two of 'em to take out
a cyborg wearing body armor.
Are you trying
to insult me?
I don't just want to know about the hit
on the shipping inspector.
You're gonna tell me what your
connection is to Locus Solus too.
Was wondering when
you'd show up...
Come get some crab boy. I hate seafood
but I'm gonna chew you up.
Come on no way is a flashy move
like gonna connect! Dumbass.
He said he knew where the inspector
was so we dealt with him...
Look I just got out of the joint
after three years!
I don't know shit about what the old
boss was up to with that company!
You still breathing
partner?
My wife and daughter's faces
flashed before my eyes...
That wasn't your wife and daughter
you were looking at.
That was the angel of death
coming for you.
I ordered you to conduct
an investigation.
I don't recall telling you to cut corners
and take the law into your own hands
...and I certainly don't recall telling you
to launch an assault on a yakuza office!
This isn't the jungle and you two aren't
Special Forces wetwork specialists!
Still mad huh?
I'm not mad.
It's just well...
I don't want to sound ungrateful
to somebody who saved my life
...but it's pretty obvious that I'll need a few
extra lives if I'm gonna team up with you.
It's just you and me working
this case full-time.
Half-assed measures aren't
gonna get us anywhere.
If there's something shady going on
between them and Locus Solus
they'll definitely
take the bait.
That's why you did something
so over the top?
If the Old Man was really angry with us
we'd both be on desk duty right now.
Pull over up there.
See ya.
You've stepped inside
the kill zone.
Don't go screwing around with
the settings on that right arm.
Updated drivers have been
known to conflict with...
...fire control software and
cause degraded functionality.
If it happens I'll come in
and get it reset.
Hey what do you think they did with
the remains of my original arm?
Don't bother.
The organic components in that arm
have been matched to your DNA.
In other words it'll be as good as
my original once I break it in...
Ow! Wait a minute
damn it!
Hey if you're bringing her here
that means you...
Sorry we broke into your
little love nest.
The thought of her sitting there
howling for her missing master
starving and covered in her
own shit broke my heart.
I may look gruff but I've
got a soft spot for dogs.
Yeah but I was the one who
took her home for the night.
My daughter was ecstatic but my wife
is pissed about the mess on the carpet.
How long did you have us
under surveillance?
It's no big deal
don't sweat it.
Damn straight it is.
Using me as a smoke screen...
It's not my fault you were
too green to spot the tail.
If you're gonna hate anyone
hate the Old Man.
Is she a clone?
Originals cost a fortune right?
Apparently this was the first type of
dog bred by artificial insemination.
It's not like you to let somebody hack
into your cyberbrain like that.
When your daily routine falls into a pattern
that's when you're vulnerable to traps.
I told you to switch
to dry food idiot.
It's her favorite. That's the only store
around here where I can get it.
Somebody pulled your strings
to make you go berserk.
You ended up putting five rounds
into your own arm
and came this close to
blowing away the store owner.
You might be off your game but there aren't
many people capable of hacking you.
Other than the Major
that is.
Why didn't they make me blow
my brains out right off the bat?
Because their goal wasn't to eliminate you
it was to create a scandal.
You busted into a mob office and sent a
dozen people to the afterlife or the hospital.
And then before the day was out
you shot up a convenience store.
Anybody would think that you're nuts or
have one serious cyberbrain malfunction.
Hey wait a minute.
This attack proves that this case isn't
a simple accident. If we back off now...
"Then what's the point of there being
a Section 9 in the first place?"
If she were here I bet
that's what she'd say.
Message from the Old Man.
"Continue the investigation."
"But until you have material
evidence there can be..."
"...no official support
from this point forward."
Guess we'll have to go check out
Locus Solus in person.
"Speed is key when preserving secrecy.
Fly to the Northern Frontier ASAP" he says.
Up north?
You two aren't
up to it?
No it's just...
But what about the dog?
The issue here is a guy in this line
of work a bachelor at that
having a dog in
the first place!
Of all the dogs in the world you had
to pick a high-maintenance breed!
Come up with something
your own damn selves!
In its heyday this was the
Etorofu Special Economic Zone
built to be the greatest
information-intensive city in the Far East.
All that's left to show it was ever here
is this forest of giant grave markers.
Its iffy sovereignty status has
made it the perfect hangout...
...for multinationals and the criminal
organizations that feed on their scraps.
A no-man's-land outside the reach of both
UN Net Police and ASEAN Cybercops.
Reminds me of that quote about how an
artifact that a single individual builds...
...is as much an expression of the builder's
genetic phenotype as the builder itself.
That guy was talking about
beaver dams and spider webs.
I'll take coralline algae and the
coral reefs they create thanks.
These are nowhere near
as pretty though.
If life's true nature is information
that's passed down via genes
then society and civilization are also nothing
more than gigantic memory systems
which makes cities huge
external memory devices.
"How precious also are thy thoughts unto
me O God! How great is the sum of them!"
"If I should count them they are
more in number than the sand."
Psalm 139 from the
Old Testament huh?
The way it calls up quotes
like that at the drop of a hat
maybe your external memory's phenotype
has a bit of your philosophical bent.
Yeah like you're one
to talk.
Sorry to interrupt fellas but we'll be over
the Locus Solus head office building soon.
I'll do a slow flyby for you guys so
hold on tight and enjoy the scenery.
All right that's all for our little side tour.
Now coming in to land.
"Angel Forms who lay intrans't
Thick as Autumnal Leaves."
"Nine dayes they fell;
confounded Chaos roard."
Quoting Milton this time?
I got news for you we aren't Satan.
The night bird calls out in sadness.
When I turn to look
the flowers had all fallen away.
It was as if all comfort...
...had vanished from the world.
As the gods leave...
...to gather in the new world
day breaks and the night bird calls out.
The blossoms beseech the gods.
"Even though in this world..."
"...we may know grief and suffering"
"our dreams shall never die"...
B-Batou!
Oh you're a real bigshot now. When did you
grow the stones to drop the "sir" with me?
I haven't forgotten
the debt I owe you!
"I never recall you to my memory
because I have never forgotten you" huh?
C'mon cut me
some slack Batou! Sir.
But I also have too much dignity to be
buttered up by you calling me "sir."
Forgive me! I beg you!
I'll be in your debt for life!
You know a guy by
the name of Kim?
Never heard
of him.
I mean guys with that name
are a dime a dozen around here.
Maybe but I'm only looking
for one Kim in particular.
Hey there's such a thing as
loyalty in my line of work.
"There are two kinds of loyalty. One
maintains secrets the other openness."
"The two cannot coexist."
Which kind do you have?
The same guy also said that without lies
there can be no truth!
I'll ask you one more time. You know
this guy named Kim don't you?
I don't know the guy!
Uh I don't know that particular Kim!
"When we face death our life
is like a puppet on a festival cart."
"As soon as one string is cut
it crumples and fades."
"Even though
in this world..."
"...we may know grief
and suffering"
"our dreams
shall never die"...
...and they fall from the branch
in anger.
Man From Machine
Well?
He started out as a long-range scout
for the military.
"Having failed in leading
having failed in following"
"...he is fit only to die
by the side of the road."
His career was shot to hell for things
like running black market arms deals...
...while he was bouncing between
Special Forces and cyberwarfare units.
In the end he wound up
your stereotypical hacker.
One of those "colorful history"
types huh?
"If an ass goes a-traveling
he'll not come back a horse."
He's just a dumb son of a bitch who
bit off more than he could chew.
You coming?
Batou. In the study
on the upper floor.
I guess we got here
too late.
He must've tried to hack into somewhere
and gotten fried by an attack barrier.
He probably wouldn't have been any
use to us even if he was still alive.
"In accordance with the deceased's wishes
we firmly decline..."
"...any offers of live flowers artificial flowers
or releasing of birds."
Hey!
"In bed he did not lie
like a corpse."
Even the great Confucius says
you shouldn't play possum.
I haven't got time to play
your stupid games.
It's been a long time Batou. Not since
the Nemuro landing operation.
I'm here
on business.
Locus Solus huh? They got into robot
manufacturing late in the game
but once they switched focus to developing
and producing high-end gynoids
their business started
to expand rapidly.
It's rumored that they're cozy
with politicians
high-ranking bureaucrats
and even organized crime.
They got paranoid about visits from
the authorities so they set up...
...their production line inside a multinational
factory ship anchored off the coast.
The dolls they make there
are fine pieces of work.
Good enough to commit murder
and then kill themselves?
If that's true
it's pretty disturbing.
I don't understand people
who try to mimic humans...
...by breathing souls
into dolls.
The definition of a truly beautiful doll is
a flesh and blood body devoid of a soul.
A corpse standing on tiptoes
teetering on the brink of collapse.
And that's why you decided to turn
yourself into a cyberized invalid?
In terms of appearance
and grace of movement
no in their very existence
humans don't hold a candle to dolls.
The flaws in man's knowledge
leads to flaws in man's reality.
That sort of perfection can only
be achieved by something...
...that possesses no consciousness
or possesses infinite consciousness.
In other words
only by dolls or gods.
Look would you mind getting down
to the business at hand?
Actually there is one other being
that is on par with dolls or gods.
Animals huh?
Shelly's skylarks are filled with the joy
of the deep subconscious
something that creatures like us with our
strong sense of self can never experience.
For the descendants of those who ate
of the fruit of the Tree of Knowledge
that's a far more difficult proposition
than becoming as gods.
So you put yourself into the body of
a doll and played dead. Is that why?
As Confucius said "Not yet understanding
life how can you understand death?"
"Few people know death..."
"...we only endure it"
"usually from determination
and even from stupidity and custom;"
"and most men only die because
they know not how to prevent dying."
But to a living doll
death is a given a fact of life.
That was the reason Kim decided
to get a full prosthetic body.
Well?
His career was shot to hell for things
like running black market arms deals...
...while he was bouncing between
Special Forces and cyberwarfare units.
In the end he wound up
your stereotypical hacker.
One of those "colorful history"
types huh?
"If an ass goes a-traveling
he'll not come back a... horse."
What's the matter?
Let's go.
Batou!
"On this day of this month the deceased
wishes to inform the public..."
"...of the happy occasion
of his death."
Hey!
This is seriously disturbing isn't it?
Trust me I know how you feel.
It's the uncertainty that maybe something
that appears to be alive actually isn't.
And the uncertainty that
on the other hand
maybe something that doesn't appear
to be alive actually is.
If you want to know what
makes dolls so unnerving
it's because they are
modelled after humans.
In other words it is because they
are no less than humanity itself.
The fear that humans might be reduced
to simple mechanisms and materials.
The fear in other words
that the human phenomenon...
...is fundamentally devoid
of meaning and purpose.
Stop this crap and let's
get down to business.
Even science which has tried to shed
light on the phenomenon of life
has played a major role
in fomenting this fear.
The belief that nature is quantifiable
leads to the conclusion...
...that humanity can also be reduced
to simple mechanical parts.
"The human body is a machine
which winds its own springs."
"It is the living image
of perpetual movement."
The 18th Century
"man as machine" theory...
...has been resurrected by cyberbrains
and prosthetic body technology.
Ever since it became possible to externalize
memory through the use of computers
man has been aggressively
mechanizing himself...
...in order to expand the upper limits
of his abilities as a living creature.
It's a manifestation of the desire to
overcome Darwinian survival of the fittest
and to break free of the evolutionary
rat race through sheer strength of will
as well as the desire to outdo the natural
world that gave birth to humanity itself.
The fantasy of a lifeform equipped
with perfect hardware...
...is what gave rise
to this nightmare.
"God forever geometrizes."
Let's go!
Batou!
How do you feel?
I... What the hell?
You were in a virtual experience maze.
Your cyberbrain got hacked.
Just like good things
come in threes
bad things also turn up
in sets of three.
You don't want to see so you don't look.
And even if you notice you say nothing.
And if you say something no one listens.
Then catastrophe comes calling.
But in our world we don't
get three chances.
If we miss that first hint
it's all over.
I thought I told you that we didn't
have time for your games.
When did you
figure it out?!
Nobody's easier to trick than somebody
who thinks he's tricking you.
You might have been
a cyberwarfare specialist
...but I'm an old
infowar pro myself.
And besides I have a guardian angel
looking over my shoulder.
Call up the hall data from that huge
external memory device of yours.
According to Jacob Grimm a golem
an artificial human was given energy...
...by inscribing the word "aemaeth"
meaning "truth" on its forehead.
But if you erase the first two letters
"ae" it becomes "meath"
meaning "death" and it turns
back to lifeless clay.
This was an oracle telling me that there
was no truth to be found here in this villa.
You're trying to tell me that someone
breached the barriers I set up?
Impossible! No one could
pull that off!
Weren't you listening?
I said I have a guardian angel.
Game's over Kim.
You're going to tell us everything.
That's an ordinary doll.
You need to learn when to quit Kim.
You think I'd fall for a stunt like that?
Batou can you say for sure
that this isn't just a continuation...
...of the reality that was manufactured
by my virtual signals?
My Ghost is whispering
to me.
Humanity is just another thread
from which the dream of life is woven.
That is if our dreams intelligence
and yes even our Ghosts
are rips and distortions that arise
in the uniform timeless matrix.
You and I are both
worthless human beings
but we're not in
the same shoes.
Folks who doesn't believe
in the Ghost...
...will never know madness schizophrenia
or a million other little things.
What little flesh you have left
will never decay.
I bet it'll keep on functioning physically
until you finally get what's coming to you.
We're really back in the
real world right?
There's nothing to distinguish between
a memory and your recollection of it.
In both cases any understanding of its
significance only comes after the fact.
Not being able to save the subjective
passage of time makes things tricky.
When you have a cyberbrain and allow
your memories to be shared externally
this is one price you're
gonna pay sooner or later.
Do you have really have a wife and kid
waiting for you at home?
Or are you still
a bachelor
sitting alone in some dingy apartment
somewhere dreaming you have a family?
Don't you want
to go find out?
If you he was gonna try that
why didn't you stop him?!
I had to find out what
his objective was.
He set his trap knowing
I'd come to him for help
then infect us with that virtual
experience to get rid of us.
Probably something
like that.
Maybe he planted a tap in my cyberbrain
when he had me dancing to his tune...
...and made me blow off
my right arm.
Just like Ishikawa said
somebody who could pull that off...
...wouldn't stop
at just that.
Locus Solus is probably
thinking the same thing.
So you anticipated this would happen
from the very beginning?
The plan was to make him think I'd fallen
into his trap to get close to him
but Kim is one talented
son of a bitch.
If I hadn't gotten that sign
I never would have made it out.
That "guardian angel"
you mentioned it isn't...
She's gone away. Out beyond
the rips in the uniform matrix.
Somewhere out in the vast net
she's fused with the entire realm.
If you're looking to prove
your own existence
there's as many ways
as there are Ghosts.
You yourself have
a daughter remember?
Back when we were in the jungle even that
bastard Kim must have understood that.
I've come out of this with
a valuable lesson too.
What's that?
That I don't have what it takes
to be your partner.
You wimping out
on me?
It's not because
of what you said
but I do want to make it back
to my daughter in one piece.
Be that as it may I'm still gonna
make you earn your paycheck.
You're not done yet?
The files we pulled from his cyberbrain
prove Locus Solus' criminal...
All we can prove is obstruction
and violating the Cyberbrain Ethics Act.
And besides our investigation
is off the books.
To prove criminal liability in the killing
rampage those gynoids went on
we need hard evidence
remember?
Maybe but Kim's
a dead end.
No he isn't.
His cyberbrain is Ghost-packed
but it's still linked to Locus Solus.
We have to finish this before they
say to hell with appearances...
...and tie up all their
loose ends.
Long ago people had
a great expression.
"When right and wrong are in doubt
beat the drums and attack."
When talk has failed
it's time for violence.
Hey! This is worlds apart from
busting into some yakuza office!
I'm not counting on your
Mateba to watch my back.
"Birds hide by flying high into the heavens
and fish by diving deep into the sea..."
- Contact made with escort.
- Roger.
I'm amazed you have the guts
to dive with a body like that.
This area's so deep that if you went down
not even we could retrieve you.
I used to know a cyborg who
went scuba diving for fun.
Yeah?
I don't know what the hell
she was thinking.
I'm playing along because
Lin vouched for you
but they say that nobody's ever gone
to that ship and lived to tell about it.
I don't know what
you are thinking.
That makes two of us.
Take us in.
Hold on tight.
Contact with sensor picket line
in 12 seconds.
I'm gonna send out a virtual signal
for 2 seconds on their channel.
Acknowledged.
I'll be this guy's wired directly to the
security supervisor's cyberbrain...
Commencing synchronization.
All right I'm in.
Send me the ship schematics.
Upload complete. Are you
piggybacking my visual feed?
Of course. I wouldn't miss the
Big Man's big infiltration.
I'm already recording.
You can be a real smartass
you know that?
"Please let the dawn..."
"...be waiting in the underworld."
Intruder alert. Reactivate
security system at level 2.
Begin facility-wide scan
of all cyberbrain activity.
Scanning for terminals where memory
usage and virus size matches.
Possible time bomb virus.
Be advised.
Unable to establish logic connection
with supervisor.
Execute reinitialization.
System reactivation complete.
Running at level 2.
Establish diversionary route
for intruder.
Rebuilding logic barrier.
Loading antibodies.
Virus scan in progress.
Trace route team
equip decoys.
Deploying full array of ambush virus
variants inside barriers.
Commencing isolation
of infected areas.
Rebuild peripheral barriers
at level 1.
Barrier 014 breached.
Barrier 032
showing type 280 error.
Enemy attack barrier
modulation pattern determined.
Commencing virus transfer.
"Please let the dawn..."
Pull out! It's too dangerous for you to stay
any longer! You'll get your brain fried!
Not yet! I can keep working
a little longer!
You dumb bastard!
Don't try to be a hero!
"...be waiting in the underworld"
the blossoms beseech the gods.
"When we face death our life is like a puppet on a festival cart."
"As soon as one string is cut it crumples and fades."
Illegal input in gynoid production line
Hadaly final processing area.
Unidentified ambush-type
virus suspected.
Deploy all antibody variants
and stop it.
Unable to track. All machines
have been activated.
Unable to establish
logic connection.
Now loading self-defense programs
for combat-model prosthetic bodies.
Alert. Abnormal startup
of bodies on THO7 line.
Security teams arm yourselves
and proceed to line at once.
Repeating...
The blossoms beseech the gods.
"Even though in this world..."
"...we may know grief and suffering"
"our dreams shall never die"
...and they fall from the branch in anger.
"And the Holy Spirit descended
in bodily form upon Him..."
Been a long time
Major.
Or what should I call you
these days?
To be precise this is just a part of me
that I uploaded via satellite.
This gynoid's cyberbrain simply
doesn't have the capacity.
The combat control programs alone
are taking up most of its free space.
This is the best I can do
for speech and facial expression.
Go straight up this corridor
about 50 meters
and there ought to be
an emergency terminal.
We'll gain access through that and
take control of the whole system.
You haven't changed
one bit.
Get moving
point man.
I've got your back.
Just like the old days.
"There are few who can hold up
a mirror and not become evil."
"A mirror does not expose evil;
rather it creates it."
Hey this is no time get philosophical!
I'm running low on ammo here.
"In short mirrors ought to be merely
glanced at not stared at."
...and they fall from the branch
in anger.
Hey are you okay?
It's just until I get control
of ship's receiver system.
Jack into the auxiliary
terminal in the floor.
Until I gain control this body's
physical functions will stop.
My only defense will be
your.30 caliber Batou.
My regular brain can handle the targeting
but I'm down to one spare clip here.
If I have to go hand-to-hand with those
things I can't make any guarantees.
I'm starting.
Illegal connection
to shipboard systems.
Shipboard? Scan for access point
and raise attack barriers.
Multiple virtual signals
at multiple terminals.
No increased fluctuations in
terminal cyberbrain activity.
Scan all external
access points.
Sever all external connections
including home office production line.
Physically isolate shipboard
input devices.
No response from emergency
control systems.
Remote ignition impossible.
Modular viruses assembling system-wide.
System-area barriers being breached.
Prepare for system reboot.
Commencing data isolation at level 1.
In the sad perpetual darkness...
...of a hundred nights
they pray to the gods of the land...
...for the egg of the next world to be born.
"When we face death our life
is like a puppet on a festival cart..."
I have control. I've locked out
all external access.
This ship is operating
in full standalone mode.
It's started moving?
The ship is heading from the
extraterritorial Northern Frontier...
...to a neighboring country
where the rule of law applies.
The ship itself is hard evidence
of Locus Solus' criminal activity.
They're gonna come
after us.
Ships will turn up before then
to escort us in.
I've already sent out
a request.
Now care to take a peek behind
the curtain and see what magic spell...
...Locus Solus used to breathe
souls into these dolls?
You don't know already?
You have your suspicions too.
Don't you.
There's no noise at all. This chamber
is completely EM-shielded?
Ghost dubbing...
The technology was able to produce
multiple degraded copies in animal tests
but it was banned when they learned
that it destroyed the brain of the original.
They take the kids they smuggled in
using the Koujinkai's routes
brainwash them and dub their Ghosts
into those gynoids' bodies.
So this is the secret behind the popularity
of Locus Solus' gynoids...
Please help us...
You came to save us!
Mr. Vaucanson said you would!
He was sure that people from the police
would come! That they would save us!
I'm a stage 4 but my friend Sowana has
already been moved up to stage 5.
She can't hear anything
and she doesn't answer me anymore.
The murdered inspector tweaked their
ethics code to try to help these children
and when he was found out he was
served up to the yakuza as their boss' killer.
That's the long
and short of it.
He said that if the robots caused accidents
someone would figure it out!
Someone would come
help us!
Didn't it ever occur to you
that there would be victims?
I'm not talking about
the humans.
Didn't you stop to think what would happen
to the dolls that were given souls?
But I...
I didn't...
I didn't want to
turn into a doll!
"We are saddened by a bird's cry
but not a fish's blood."
"Blessed are those
with voices."
If those dolls
had voices
I bet they would have screamed
"I don't want to be a human!"
Let me ask you something.
Are you happy the way you are now?
I haven't seen things that way
for a long time.
At the very least I can say that
I'm at peace with myself now.
"Let a man walk alone
let him commit no sin."
"Let him have
few wishes..."
"...like an elephant
in the forest."
Don't forget
Batou.
Whenever you access the net
I'll be there at your side.
Time to go.
Gods in Heaven smile upon us.
She appeared to you on that ship
didn't she? Your guardian angel.
Being tight-lipped again huh? Why?
You think I'll include it in my report?
I'll come pick you up
at 0800 tomorrow.
I need to repay you for
looking after my gal too.
How about it?
Want to come in?
Getting all warm and fuzzy with
someone else's family isn't my thing.
Daddy!
Did you bring me a present?
Where's my present?
- I didn't forget. Here.
- Yay!