CONDEMNED TO DEATH BY HIS PEERS
FOR REBELLION
HORUS FROM HIERAKONOPOLIS,
THE GOD OF HEAVENS,
HAS SEVEN DAYS TO SEE THE EARTH
OF MANKIND
ONCE MORE,
THE EARTH HE HELPED CREATE.
SEVEN DAYS: THE TIME FOR ONE BEAT
OF THE DIVINE HEART.
NOT A SECOND MORE.
BEFORE BEING DEPRIVED
OF HIS IMMORTALITY
BUT EVEN THE GODS FEAR DEATH
Heru?
Horus?
Meru
It's time
Ta em sertu en maa abtet!
Make the most of your last moments
Seven days, HORUS, seven hourglasses...
Not a second more.
Semut bat.
Trust me
I know you're there...
Hey! Look over there!
What is this?
A naked man with a bird head.
What's going on? I lose control.
There is no answer...
Right me, right me
Children...my humans children.
I am back.
...Now, I'm also in charge of the nano
implants department...
...but we concentrate more
on synthetic skin.
No hard feelings, then.
Thank you for reminding me!
Can I take two?
No. Only one this time.
There're maybe no hard feelings
but you're still tight-fisted?
Fuck you, Elma.
You should be so lucky.
That girl's dangerous.
She must be on pretty powerful stuff...
She managed to damage a carrier
when they were selecting them...
When they were rounding them up,
you mean...
That's why I'm interested in her...
I see that you're involved in illegal
medicine more than ever.
Resistance medicine,
there's a difference.
You really like her, don't you?
I'm taking her with me.
I'll need a supply of antibiotics,
even old ones...
and microneedles...
Not so fast, darling!
I want a detailed report of all
the analyses you perform on her.
And don't even try to pretend that
you've lost the file!
You can have her, but I want the file!
His mother has been treated...
He's waiting for her
to be returned to him.
How old are you?...
Let's go...
... But you openly accuse
Senator Allgood
of manipulating public opinion.
Do you think he's the one who organized
the pyramid affair
in order to get elected?
No. His influence
doesn't run that deep.
It's obvious that the pyramid
is extraterrestrial,
Like the INTRUSION zone
in Central Park...
I don't agree with the view
that Intrusion
is a matrix of dangerous mutants.
This rumor was spread by Allgood
to serve the interests of EUGENlCS.
Scientists have proved that Intrusion
is a GATEWAY to PARALLEL
or EXTRATERRESTRIAL worlds.
We'll have to face the fact that
we're not alone in the Universe...
But in practical terms your program
doesn't seem very satisfactory.
You're putting all the blame
on the outgoing candidate,
Senator Allgood.
...I'm also talking about
the medical dictatorship
that ALLGOOD has imposed on NYC,
with the active participation
of EUGENICS.
I'm talking about raids,
illegal experiments,
unauthorized blood-tests
and organ removal,
people going missing...
I'm talking about GLOBUS 1,
you know what that is, don't you?
It's the 'freezer'
used by the mad scientists
that work for EUGENICS'...
But you do agree there's a real
security problem, don't you?
That series of murders on Level 2...
That's police business.
I have full confidence
in the Federal Police.
What a bitch!
A bitch,
but a fast learner about politics.
That's what I mean! A whore!
That's enough... About those murders.
How many have been reported so far?
Four.
Who's in charge of the case?
Inspector Froebe.
He's a specialist in the abnormal.
He thinks it's the work
of a serial killer.
Froebe is no specialist.
Hunting is all he lives for,
ever since he had his face chewed
on by the Dayak.
He's a real psychopath.
He's a liability.
I don't agree, Miss Liang.
Froebe is a good cop, and anyway,
he's politically neutral.
"Neutral!" ..."Neutral"
doesn't exist...
There're only men and women...
Humans and aliens.
The integrated and the rejected.
The whole fucking universe
is split into two...
That makes five!
In less than 48 hours,
that's got to be a record...
Exactly the same M. O.
It's just as if the body had exploded
from the inside.
I was told there was a witness.
Yeah! He's right over there,
he's waiting for you
Back at my office in an hour.
You're alright?
I'll see you at Froebe's, OK?
Yeah... Yeah... All right!
I'll see you there.
Are you sure you're alright?
Hi...Mmm...
What can I get you?
He wants to know if they're diseased.
He asked you a question.
I... I'm fine, thanks.
All your organs?!
I've... I've changed my lungs.
They're a Chinese model.
Not bad... Pretty attractive...
and... I...
I have a new bladder too,
no problem there.
Still don't want a drink?
Six.
No. Seven.
Outside the bar...the witness.
The one I never got to see.
That's right, the giant.
He's the seventh and the agent who
was supposed
to bring him to you was the sixth.
Reminds you of the DAYAKS, doesn't it?
Cold blooded carnage like this,
right up their alley.
The Dayaks are extinct.
They were all exterminated after
the riots, thirty years ago.
Except the one that got you....
Thank you, Sandy.
It's not going to hold but I can't do anything anymore...
I did warn you.
Only 35 percent of your original
metabolism remains
you've modified
or replaced all the rest.
I have a contract with EUGENICS...
I had guessed that much.
Tell my colleague I sent you.
He's a specialist
in nano- surgical repairs...
Don't leave it too long.
Thank you Doctor.
I'm so sorry, Jill. New Yorkers all
seem to have gone insane...
Where was I? Oh, Yes,
the lapse in your memory.
I was wondering what it is that
you don't want to remember so badly,
that you're this blocked?
Put it another way;
what are you trying to forget?
I can't remember anything,
there's a subtle difference.
But it seems
that you remembered to take
strong doses of potentially dangerous
substances as yet unidentified.
Do you have any on you?
Is your supplier on level 3,
in Little Paris,
amongst the non humans?
Some of them are very decent beings.
You, for example...
I have to tell you that
in 20 years of medicine
I've never seen
a guinea pig quite like you...
I've never seen such a heart,
lungs, or a womb like that... Never.
You're built like someone who
was born less than three months ago...
Maybe that's what you want to forget?
Or what you're not sure about?
When did you get to New York?...
And how?
Some of the vertebrate animals
on this planet shed their skin,
You are going through
the same process...
Listen to my offer! Work for me.
Let me conduct
a thorough medical examination,
take some samples,
test some medication...
If you trust me,
you won't have anything to worry
about any more.
You'll be covered and legal...
And more importantly,
I'll get you a card.
I have a contract
with the Western hysteria ...
You can live there...
You're the greatest mystery
of nature I've ever come across...
John...
I got picked up in a Eugenics raid.
I shot a carrier...
It could have gone very badly...
A human woman doctor saved me.
She offered me a job
and legal housing...
Accept it...
As a guinea pig...
Apparently my body
is only three months old,
and my organs aren't
in the right place...
Not in the right place,
according to whose criteria?
You see that pyramid monument...
Do you think it's in its right place?
And me? Do you think I am?
There's something important
you should know.
This planet is rejecting me,
Jill...This atmosphere,
this oxygen, it's burning me up...
I have to take care
of you before it's too late.
I'm getting old, Jill,
I've been around for centuries...
I'm confused
Oh... My God...
Jesus!
This one's empty!
Restricted area.
... A flying pyramid,
a serial killer on the loose
and now a chunk
of prison falling from the sky.
Is someone out to sabotage
my political career or what?
It's like in one of those
Greek tragedies, Senator,
all the elements will fall into place...
What are you doing here,
Inspector FROEBE?
I'm looking for three
of my men who have disappeared.
Your serial killer again?
Don't think so.
Here. A gift for you.
What is it?
You should know better than me.
Give me that!
This is way out of your league.
I haven't found
the man who goes with this...
"Remember...
Remember the sight we saw, my soul,
that beautiful soft summer morning..."
"...round a turning in the path..."
Thank you...
..."a disgusting carcass
on a bed scattered with stones,
its legs in the air like
a woman in heat..."
"Remember the sight we saw, my soul,
that beautiful soft summer morning...
round a turning in the path,
a disgusting carcass
on a bed scattered with stones,
its legs in the air like a woman
in heat..."
"... like a fountain
with its rhythmical sobs.
I can hear it clearly flowing
with a long,
murmuring sound, but I touch my body
in vain to find the wound..."
"...I am the vampire of my own heart,
One of the great outcasts condemned
to eternal laughter
who can no longer smile...".
Am I dead? I must be dead.
And you...
I know you,
you are from Hierakonopolis.
The god of the heavens.
I'm flattered, Nikopol,
wretched human.
...Anubis can't be far away?
The guardian of the tombs...
The god of the dead...
Don't ever speak
that jackal's name again,
you understand? Only my name...
Only me...
OK.. OK...
My leg!... Where is my leg?
You can see you're not dead...
The dead don't feel pain...
The dead don't bleed either.
Yeah,
I'm alive and I'm bleeding like a pig.
Listen carefully, I won't say it twice.
For two of your days now,
I have been looking for a host body,
for reasons that go far beyond any
human concerns.
I need a body
to welcome me and serve me.
You... You seem to be suitable.
I've tested seven humans before you
and rejected them all... But you,
your body is clean.
You come from the past...
Thirty years of hibernation...
Your body won't reject me.
We are compatible.
What year is it? Who set me free?
2095 after your Jesus Christ.
Your release is an accidental escape.
I was supposed to be let out in 2096.
I was released a year ahead
of schedule.
I've gained a year
but Iost a leg. Fuck!
Forget the old one...
Here's a new one.
Yes... Thank you for calling.
That was the forensic scientist
from Globus...
And?
The leg has been identified.
Well... it belongs to... Nikopol.
Perfect
There's no way.
This thing weighs a ton.
I'll never be able to move.
That's right.
Without me you won't be able to move.
And by the way,
from now on you won't be able
to do much of anything without me...
I accept that I'm not dead now.
But I hope I'm dreaming this.
Please God let this be a nightmare.
Let this all be a nightmare...
You believe in God?
I don't even have that to fall back on.
I suggest you believe in me, Nikopol...
Do I have a choice?
I'm afraid not.
Now, rise and walk.
I've relinquished control, Nikopol,
you can have a bit of autonomy now.
I want you to know that everything
is going perfectly well.
Your body is very comfortable
and tolerates me beautifully...
And above all you're most elegant.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Elegant, famous and subversive.
Just what I like ...
It seems you're the instigator
of all this fighting
that's been going on without you...
Not bad for a human...
Would it be too much to ask
for just a bit more autonomy?
I'd like to choose my own clothes,
with the Iittle free
will I have left...
Your happiness is my priority,
Nikopol, Mr. Free spirit.
How is Doctor Elma Turner?
Never been better.
Welcome to the Western Hysteria Hotel.
39th floor. Room 12.
Any friend of Dr Turner's
is a friend of mine.
Por ti Ketro...
That's for me?... Thanks...
What's your name?
Willy... Ketarakado... Willy...
Willy? OK, I'll call you Willy.
And you can call me Jill...
Temperature fourty four degrees
Number of teeth: thirty seven unit,
thirty seven
No mammal dental blades,
unknown Buccal profile unknown...
Thank you Jill now you can make
the food test.
...with a list that's getting longer.
Eight victims, all male,
This just in,
Senator ALLGOOD has announced
that he will be on the Zeppelin
when the scientific delegation
and leading
Egyptologists make another attempt
to contact the inhabitants
of the Pyramid...
...the hydrometer rate
is down today in
Brooklyn for the fourth day running.
On INTRUSION, however, no change.
Snow, ice,
temperature 23 below freezing...
Twelve attempted break-ins
into lNTRUSlON have been
reported: there are no survivors.
Do not approach the Central Park area.
DOWN! ... DOWN! ... DOWN!
...EVERY BODY DOWN!
Aber od neb aber, Bastet?
Are we cheating or not, Bastet?
Aber, Anubis,aber .
We're cheating,Anubis, we're cheating
You don't understand? Nikopol is alive!
Maybe not.
It was reported that He was shot
by a department store security guard
and fell a hundred meters...
But they couldn't find the body.
Are you telling me the man can fly?
I can put you on to Huxley,
Froebe's right hand man.
He's in charge of...
That's OK, Jonas. Thanks.
You can leave us now...
Right. Get the hell out
of here! Beat it!
He knows everything.
I know he knows everything,
and his phenomenal memory
is stuffed with enough evidence
concerning your late father's
financial dealings
and his illegal experiments
on alien populations to cause EUGENlCS
some very serious problems...
I am aware of that.
Up until now we've only had the spirit
of Nikopol to deal with,
but now we have him in flesh and blood.
No one's ever come back from GLOBUS.
Well, HE has. Why wasn't he executed
30 years ago, anyway?
Are you crazy?... Are you crazy?
To make a hero out of him,
a martyr to their lousy revolution?
What do you want, riots,
assassination?!
It is the last prototype
of the "hunter" version.
Fast, ferocious and totally illegal.
He'll be quicker
than Froebe and his men.
Are you sure?
No, but it's the only solution...
Apart from your "protege".
No, not him...
Let's try this one first.
Come in!
You're early!
We have no time to lose
Is he ready?
Have you re-activated him yet?
No. I'll need about an hour.
I wanted to make sure you really
wanted him.
We do.
OK.
What's this! What happened?
Nothing of any importance,
really, nothing.
Do you like women?
Women?
Women...
My most beautiful and most important
creation on this planet...
Your story doesn't make much sense...
You're looking for a blue-haired girl
with white skin...
What's this all about, and,
how do you know she comes here?
In the same way that I knew
I'd find her on planet Earth,
in New York City...
Intuition, Nikopol,
the intuition of the gods...
So. What's so special about her
that warrants such a display of talents?
Is she Miss Universe or what?
You don't think I've come all this way
for a mere human being, do you?
Now I know more about you...
Why are you doing all this for me?
It's a political and social fight.
My Spirit of Nikopol coming out.
Besides, your case interests me...
I think you like me...
Isn't that what you were thinking?
You could say that.
How did you guess?
Do you read minds too?
You could say that...
It's true, I do like you
and I feel close to you, Jill,
whoever you are...
Mutant or whatever...
Although you are beginning
to scare me.
Let's try a little experiment.
To test this talent of yours...
I'm going to think of a question
and you're going to answer. Ready?
Ready.
I've asked the question.
You want to know
if I've started testing
the foods you prescribed for me,
if I took a blood
test three hours later and
if I took ... notes.
Answer: Yes!
I did everything I was supposed to do,
and I found everything absolutely
delicious...
I'm a professional guinea pig.
Have you tasted everything?
For dinner, yes. I ate it all.
And you ate everything at once?
In the prescribed quantities?
I weighed everything.
I just changed a couple of the recipes.
I didn't have anything to cook with
so I ate the fish called monkfish raw
and the lamb too.
They're not bad together.
How many meals do you have a day?
Two a week.
She's not bad.
Not surprising, you idiot.
She's the one.
John...
Come Jill, come...
You'll be my last
and my most beautiful Intrusion...
Listen carefully...
For thousands of Earth years I've been
introducing people into
the four corners of the galaxy...
People misplaced by the vagaries
of the Universe...
You're a misplaced person, Jill...
And I'll never know your origins...
You appeared deep in the heart
of INTRUSION about three months ago...
That's where I took charge of you...
The blue pills stop your past
from re-emerging
and let the present... invade you.
Your metamorphosis is on the verge
of completion...
From now on your place
is on this planet...
What about you? Aren't you staying?
I'm a passer at the end of his cycle.
I'm already dreaming of a void...
I'm afraid...
Afraid of what?
...of becoming human.
Tell me about your job
with Doctor Elma Turner
Can I buy you a drink?
Don't you think I have enough already?
Well, I don't see any cognac,
or sake...
Tequila... Slivovitsa...
I'm working. Do you mind?
A vodka. Make it a Tarkovskaia,
please.
I like your hair. It's very nice.
It goes very well with... white skin...
Is it a new thing in make-up?
Kabuki style maybe?
You must be an actress.
You're expecting something from me...
The answer is No.
You're going to need someone
to take you home.
What makes you think that?
You have no other choice.
One for the road.
I like... this one.
How about you, young lady?
We are going to get along fine.
It's very important
to have the same tastes..
No!
We've got more important things
to do than fight each other...
Address?... Western Hysteria Hotel...
You are Inspector John Emerson Huxley
and you have a black box in your brain.
Give it to me, please.
Or I'll have to go in and take it...
It goes very well with...white skin...
I don't have a room.
Which Level are you from?
I'm above levels...
This is Level 2 and the hotel's full.
The hotel maybe... but your bed is not.
Ladies first...
Control, Miss. Your papers.
My papers?
Your card if you prefer.
Thank you, Miss.
Do you have any weapons,
explosives...
Any history of violent conduct?
I hate violence.
Are you comfortable here?
Yes, fine.
Yes... I hate violence but I do like
to caress myself with bird feathers...
preferably black ones.
It's a bit small isn't it?
Don't you have a bathroom?
No. No bathroom.
I've decided never to wash again. Ever!
Who are you? This is my bathroom!
What are you doing in my bathroom?
Who are you?
We had a drink together last night.
You had several, in fact...
it's not surprising you can't remember.
Alcohol has no effect on me.
What's happening here?
What about the door?
That door wasn't there a moment ago.
Did you do that?
I'm no carpenter.
Be careful...Those things can go off
all by themselves.
Shut up, human!
What happened last night?
What did you do to my body?
So?
What did I do to your body?...
We had sexual intercourse...
You and I...
Well...
Maybe not just the two of us alone...
What do you mean by
"sexual intercourse"?
At times last night you gave
the impression
you knew perfectly well...
I wi...
I could tell you the truth...
What truth?
Bloody fuckin'god...
What did you make me do?
Fuck you!!!
What are we waiting for?
The answers
to the questions I asked him.
He can't talk anymore,
but we may be able to piece together
recent events from his subconscious.
Well can he be... repaired?
He can be treated.
A Dayak?!
A fake. A replica
of a Dayak, humanized.
We found some synthetic red epidermis
signed EUGENICS under his fingernails.
Leave us now.
Rape...
Rape?
You made me commit rape.
She consented. We, Gods,
have physical appetites, you know...
Which we have more than aptly
demonstrated for thousands of years...
You really are a piece of shit.
You think everything
is yours for the taking.
My body, that girl's body,
all the others you murdered...
We'll do it your way next time,
if you wish...
Next time? Do what my way?
Next time we make love to her.
We must make love again with that...
young lady...
No way!
Don't you like her?
I'm not sharing my body anymore,
is that clear?
Not for fucking or for anything else.
That's the end of the line.
You go your way, I'll go mine!
Nikopol, Nikopol...
You're talking
as if you had the choice.
You can walk perfectly
normally if I want you to...
But if I don't...
Don't forget this either...
Fuck you!
Right, but let's fuck her again first.
Can you describe him?
Rather average...
from what I can remember...
Human looking...
What about his... penis?
Human looking too?
Have you already had relations
of this nature before?
Relations? Human?... Social?...
Sexual.
Intercourse...
I think you've experienced
it but you don't remember...
The drugs... The pills...
I don't know who's treating you
but it shows...
Even your organs are positioning
themselves correctly.
Thank you for trusting me, Jill...
I trust John... Only John.
Are you testing me? Is that it?
That's him, I recognize him!
And that is the girl...
This is all that we've kept of her.
Her lachrymal secretions.
That should be enough.
This kind of DAYAK
has olfactory capabilities 500 times
superior to ours.
My favorite moving molecular lab.
He's a real hunter...
You taste good.
I'm proud of myself
for having found you.
You have to tell me where I can find
the one who's with you.
I don't know who you're talking about.
You'd better know who
I'm talking about.
Shh...
Jill has been through some really
difficult moments...
I've had to erase them from her memory.
We must protect her... And love her...
We must IMPREGNATE her!
So that's it?...
Can I count on you, Nikopol?
I knew I could ...
"Ceaselessly
by my side moves the Demon;
He swims around me
like impalpable air;
I swallow and feel it burn my lungs
And fill them
with eternal desire and guilt..."
Still already here?
You really don't
have anywhere else to go?
I really don't have the choice...
I only have you ...
Are you feeling alright?
Shouldn't I be?
Been in a fight?
There's a blank in my memory...
Maybe you're the one who hit me!
Why did you spend thirty years
in hibernation?
Afraid of growing older?
How do you know that?
I can mind read a bit.
But yours...
I don't understand a thing.
I know you raped me last night.
But I can't find
the memory in your mind.
To be quite honest,
it's not very clear for me either.
We should do it again
and try to understand...
You owe me that.
I was sentenced to hibernation
for trying to protect people like you.
No one is like me.
I'll go along with that...
Well, what do you read in my mind now?
OK. I'll buy you a drink.
I'd love a bottle of Bordeaux...
It's been ages...
Never heard of it.
You've travelled in space and time.
You're colder than a block of ice
and it suits you so fine.
Who are You?
I thing you like me
What are you doing to me?
To me Who are you?
I'm confused
I can't remenber anything
I'm a guinea pig. A human woman
You can call me Jill
You're expecting something from me
The answer is no
Aaah! It's cold!
Sorry, it's my leg.
I should have warned you...
It's a bit icy, of course.
Not much blood circulation down there.
It would be a shame
to Iet a few degrees...of temp...
temperature interrupt us...
Sorry Jill... Sorry...
Calm down, Jill... Calm down.
Something in the air's changed since
last time Anubis, don't you find
John! I'm scared!
John! Please come back!
I'm here Jill!
It's too dangerous to cross over now.
It's not ready yet,
and you aren't either.
Tomorrow, I hope.
INTRUSION is a gateway which
will close behind me,
and disappear with me...
It will reappear somewhere else,
other passers will come,
but you'll be the last creature
to use it.
John...
Yes?
I've met someone.
Good... Your life
as an earth dweller has begun.
Meeting humans, feeling desire...
Being in love...
One of the most beautiful feelings
you'll experience here...
But I love you. You first!
Love is very different here...
What should I do?
Cry... Whenever you feel the need,
just cry...
Where is she?
Where the fuck is she?!
I already told you.
She went for a walk.
You have to understand her...
But you're right, NlKOPOL,
you're right to want to hurt me,
even if I don't feel a thing...
Hit me again, harder.
You piece of shit.
Your objectives are shit,
your filthy rapist god ambitions
are shit!!
You're full of shit!
Coming from a human, remarks like
that don't carry much weight.
You're damaging that girl...
You're damaging Jill!
You're destroying something
really beautiful.
You don't destroy what you love.
You shouldn't have let her go...
She'll be back...
We still have to make love
to her again...
It isn't over yet...
All right, the impregnation!
I nearly forgot that minor detail.
What is this obsession of yours?
An obsession about how
little time I have left.
I really feel for you...
My name is Doctor Elma Turner...
I'm looking for one of my patients.
It's been a long time since anybody's
come in here looking to be cured.
Her name is Jill.
She told me she was a regular here.
You must know her...
White skin, blue hair...
I don't know any humans,
personally, that is.
Jill isn't really human...
How much do you know?
You must be John?
And you must be Elma Turner.
I have something to tell her.
Something rather important.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
I need to see her.
I don't believe that will be necessary.
Everything is happening
on a different level now...
What do you mean by that?
Where is she?
At least, tell me she's okay...
White skin, blue hair...
Interesting...
Let me introduce myself...
lnspector Froebe.
Did you powder up face
for the occassion?
It's not your business.
My friend, my dear, dear friend...
Ayak meao venaseo filmea.
Kyle, It's been a long time ...
Too long. I know.
I still feel the tension inside you.
The hubris.
Like five years ago when you sneaked
out without my permission...
and took a bite out
of Inspector Froebe... Remember?
lne lassa fine ninu, Ayak?
Do you need me for something Kyle?
Yes.
Have a taste of this!
Find him and finish the rest!
Still alive?
I know... this split personality
is not an easy thing to deal with
But I'm the one on the front line...
until proven otherwise...
Are you alone?
So he's gone?
The rapist who lives inside your body
and forces me
to have sexual intercourse?
I think so, but I'm not sure,
and above all I don't know ...
That wasn't a very smart thing to do.
The blue of my tears stains human
skin for good...
I feel blue... for you.
I should have shot
you the first time we met.
There's still time.
Thank you, Nikopol. Thank you...
Shh! She's asleep.
Young women like her are rare.
Extremely rare.
There are only a few
of them in the entire universe.
No-one knows why they appear
in one world or another.
They don't even know who they are,
themselves, and the power they have.
What power?
The greatest power of all.
The power to procreate with gods.
I get it. I'm just the empty shell...
the vehicle delivering
the divine seeds...
That's not going to alter
my opinion of you, ...
I don't want to go.
Jonas can represent me.
Don't Iet me down Kyle.
Don't prove to me what
I already know you are...
This is all your fault.
You're the one who dragged me
into this.
Have you just figured that out?
Sure, Kyle! You're the pawn
and I'm the player!
But I've got news for you,
you little bitch!
You're a pawn too! EUGENlCS' pawn.
Who is EUGENlCS? Huh? Who?
You're right on that one.
But I'm a superior pawn.
Your superior pawn,you understand?
Now, get up off your fat ass,
move into your TRlPLE XL clothes,
say a little prayer that...
... "your" DAYAK finds "your" NlKOPOL,
and go and negotiate
with Ancient Egypt...
MOVE IT!!
Could you forget me if you had to?
What sort of a question is that?
Seriously.
If you didn't have the choice.
Could you forget me?
No.
Well, I might forget you...
Against my will.
Without wanting to.
What are you trying to say?
Things are going to happen to me
that are out of my control.
I've already been through that.
But I'm able to control
the future for two... Or more...
You're pretty sure of yourself,
aren't you?
How can you tell?
Anyway, when you say two,
who are you alluding to?
Are you thinking about you and me,
or are you thinking about you and him.
The one inside your body... the rapist.
I'm thinking about us.
Wouldn't he be jealous?
Right now, for instance,
I know he's here, between us...
I can sense him.
The rapist wants you to know he
will never do that again.
When I kiss you, am I kissing him too?
And when he raped me,
did you enjoy it?
John!
Are you always so slow, lnspector?
What are you waiting for?
An old friend of mine...
The suspect vehicle just crossed 49th
and Madison on the second section.
All patrols on alert.
I repeat: all patrols on alert.
We're wasting precious time,
Inspector...
Jill's in danger.
Carefull...
The engine's highly tuned.
Just like you!
I'm on their tail...
Who's shooting?
Hold your fire!
Who's mortal in here?
...I mean,
who can die a violent death...
Well, I feel somewhat mortal...
I don't think so, Mister...?
Mr ...
Jill!!
Where's the Pyramid?
Where's the Senator?
It's here.
Come on...
It's here, Jill. It's time!
We're in the heart of INTRUSION.
The dead center.
John!?
Your time has come.
This red pill is the final stage
of your treatment.
It will make you human for good.
A human woman...
A human woman.
Will I forget everything?...
Everyone?
You are going to write yourself
a new story...
Swallow it!
The void, Jill... The void...
Forget me...Forget
JOHN!?!
...where the fuck are you?
I need you... I need you now!
You must be Anubis, God of the Dead...
I admire you so much!
Eraid! You, fucking bastard.
You'll never speak that
jackal's name again!
Sep nuk pas, Heruss.
Time's up!
Anuu mesen arit nef xupu!
This is the end of your Eternity!
Suten bat, akhet semut, suten bat!
Be patient brothers, I'm coming!
Nikopol, you have been much more
than a body to me.
I wish I could do more to thank you...
...But you're running out of time,
I know...
I sincerely hope your life
as a human is a happy one.
You will no longer feel the burden
of your leg.
You'll see, there will always
be a little bit of me left inside you...
I don't know how I should take that.
I will never be far from you, Jill,
ever again...
Ever...
Do I know you?
Senu bat efu unnut xau?
I'm back! Were you bored without me?
Kourou nevo pas
The sentence is binding
Bes su xet, nes su xet tekau pa neter.
I'm ready to face it...Without waiting
Set et fao
Now, then!
Nikopol, serial number N-7,
you are under arrest
for attempted escape.
You have one year left
on your sentence.
Sorry, but...
He was in there, wasn't he?
Who?
The Killer...
You must know a lot about him.
Yeah. He's a friend...
How does he kill, I'd give a lot
to know the answer to that.
Jill!
...And New York City Officials annouces
the opening of Central Parks Intrusion
to Public Access.
Do not forget that the temperature
is unusually low.
Take a break! New orbital holidays!
Forget archaic politics,
and say Yes to Liangs projects
for you and your City.
And for you, who can still read,
don't forget
"Spirit of Nikopol's Story",
by the man from the past,
Nikopol himself. A Subversive Cult Book
By the way, thanks for your book.
I could not put it down.
What about her?
"Her"?
HER!
Do you like Paris?
Oh, I'm sorry. He's so cheeky,
did he hurt you?
No, not at all. He's just fine...
Couldn't be better...
I'm terribly sorry.
My name is Jill.
I'm NlKOPOL.
How do you like this planet?
It has its charm...
Mais "Tout cela ne vaut
pas le poison qui decoule
de tes yeux, de tes yeux verts,
Lacs ou mon ame tremble et se
voit a l'envers...
Mes songes viennent en foule
Pour se desalterer
a ces gouffres amers."
"But all that is not worth the prodigy
Of you saliva, Jill,
That bites my soul, and dizzies it,
and swirls it down remorselessly,
Rolling it, fainting,
to the underworld!"