<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<html>
<head>
</head>
<body>
  <para id="0">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Once upon a timein a far away land...a young princelived in a shining castle.Although he had everythinghis heart desired...the prince was spoiled,selfilsh and unkind.But then,one winter's night...an old beggar womancame to the castle...and offered hima single rose...in return for shelterfrom the bitter cold.Repulsed by herhaggard appearance...the prince sneered at the giftand turned the old woman away .But she warned him not to bedeceived by appearances...for beauty is found within.And when he dismissed her again,the old woman's ugliness melted away....to reveala beautiful enchantress.The prince tried to apologize,but it was too late...for she had seen thatthere was no love in his heart .And as punishment, she transformed himinto a hideous beast...and placed a powerful spellon the castle and all who lived there .Ashamed ofhis monstrous form...the beast concealed himselfinside his castle...with a magic mirror ashis only window to the outside world.The rose she had offered...was truly an enchanted rose...which would bloomuntil his 21st year.If he could learnto love another...and earn her love in returnby the time the last petal fell...then the spellwould be bro ken.If not,he would be doomed...to remain a beastfor all time.As the years passed...he fell into despairand lost all hope...for who could ever learnto love a beast?</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">...Эн ЗбНбЮЗК ЗбУЗИЮЙ(бг ГЮКб еРЗ ЗбСМб нЗ (гЗнЯб(Ед бг КЯд гд ЮКб (КнСЗдУ УКнПгЗдЯнЭ МЪбеЗ ГНП КИПж ж ЯГдеЗЭЪбКЯ ЕРЗрїУГОСМЯ гд едЗеРЗ гУКНнб -бнУ Ед ЯдК ЮП ХггК ЗбгЯЗд -нЭЦб Гд нЯжд гЭКжНЗр нЗ ГОнГдК КШбИ гдн гОЗбЭЙ ЗбЮЗдждГдЗ ГШбИ гдЯц Гд КСКЯИн ОШГЗдУн ЕЫбЗЮ ЗбИЗИЕде гЭКжНгд ЮКб (КнСЗдУ УКнПгЗд)їбЗ ГНПбЗТЗб (КнСЗдУ УКнПгЗд) НнЗр(гСНИЗр нЗ (КнСЗдУГШбЮжЗ ЗбЕдРЗСгЗРЗ нМСнїбЗЎ бЗгЗРЗ дЭЪб ЗбВдїдСЯЦЗбеЗСИждгд егїгЪн ЮЗЖгЙ ИГУгЗЖегЗЮСГеЗ бн гд ЭЦбЯ(гЗнЯб УЯжЭнбП)гедПУ ЕдФЗЖнУМд ОгУ УджЗК ббУШж ЗбгУбН(ИднЗгнд гЗнбТ ЭСЗдЯбнд)ЦЗИШ УЗИЮ ИЗбМнФ ЗбГгСнЯнУМд ЛгЗд УджЗК бНнЗТЙ ИЦЗЖЪ гУСжЮЙ(Мжд ГИСжКТн)(ТЪнг ЪХЗИЙ ЪЗЖбЙ (ГИСжКТн</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">www.titlovi.comNekada davno u dalekojzemlji...u sjajnom dvorcu ћiveo jemladi princ.Iako je imao sve љtomu srce poћeli...princ je bio razmaћen,sebiиan i drzak.Jedne zimske noжi...stara prosjakinja je doљlau dvorac...i ponudila mu ruћu...u zamenu za skloniљteod oљtre zime.Odbijen njenom ruћnoжom...princ se podsmehnuo poklonui odbio staricu.Ona mu je rekla daspoljaљnji izgled vara,jer se lepota nalazi u duљi.Kada ju je ponovo odbio,njena je ruћnoжa isиeznula...i otkrilaprelepu vilu.Princ je se izvinio, alibilo je prekasno.Ona je videla dau njegovom srcu nema ljubavi.Za kaznu, pretvorila ga jeu uћasnu zver...i bacila иini na иitav dvoraci sve koji su u njemu ћiveli.Posramljena svojim izgledom...zver se skrivala u dvorcu...a njegov jedini prozor u svetbilo je иarobno ogledalo.Ruћa koju mu je dala...bila je zaista иarobna.Cvetaжe do njegovog21. roрendana.Ako nauиi da volii ta ljubav bude uzvraжena dokposljednja latica ne otpadne...иini жe biti skinute.Ako ne, biжe osuрen...da ostane zver zasva vremena.Kako su godine prolazile,</se>
  </para>
  <para id="1">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Every daylike the one beforeLittle townfull of little peopleWaking up to sayThere goes the bakerwith his tray like alwaysThe same oldbread and rolls to sellEvery morningjust the sameSince the morningthat we came- To this poor provincial town- Good morning, Belle.- Morning, monsieur.- Where you off to?The bookshop. I just finishedthe most wonderful story...- about a beanstalk and an ogre and--- That's nice.Marie, the baguettes!Hurry up!Look, there she goesThe girl is strange, no questionDazed and distractedCan't you tell- Never part of any crowd- 'Ca use her head's up on some cloudNo denying she's a funny girlthat Belle- Bonjour- Good dayHow is your family- Bonjour- Good dayHow is your wife- Ineed six eggs- That's too expensiveThere must be morethan this provincial life- Ah, Belle!- Good morning.- I've come to returnthe book I borrowed.- Finished already?Oh, I couldn't put it down.Have you got anything new ?Not since yesterday .That's all right.I'll borrow this one.That one?But you've read it twice!Well, it's my favourite!Far-off places...daring sword fights, magic spells,a prince in disguise.If you like it all that much,it's yours .- But, sir!- I insist.Well, thank you.Thank you very much.Look, there she goesThat girl is so peculiarI wonder ifshe's feeling well- With a dreamy, far- off look- And her nose stuck in a bookWhat a puzzleto the rest of us is Belle</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">(КФЗСбТ ИжКжФнЯ) ЗбФенС ИЬ(еЗнжЗнС)УКжд ЪЗгЗр бМСнгЙ ЮКб гд ЗбПСМЙ ЗбЛЗднЙ(ЭСдЗдПж УжЯСн)ОгУ УджЗК ббУСЮЙ(ПЗЭнП ГИжбУЯнУ) ЗбФенС ИЬ(КжндС)ОгУ УджЗК ббУСЮЙ ЗбЯИСм(ЛнжПжС ИЗМжнб) ЗбФенС ИЬ(Кн ИЗМ)УМд гПм ЗбНнЗЙ бУК НЗбЗК ЗОКШЗЭ ж ЗЫКХЗИж ЮКб гд ЗбПСМЙ ЗбГжбм(ж (бндЯжбд ИжСжТгд ЗбгЭКСЦ Гд нКг ЕЪПЗге ЗбГУИжЪ ЗбЮЗПгбМСнгЙ ЮКб ФЮнЮ (СнджбПТ) СЖнУЙ ЗбМгежСнЙгдР гКм ж ег ОЗСМ ГУжЗС ЗбгЯЗдїгдР ЗбЛЗгдЙ гУЗБ ГгУУЯжЭнбП) ж (ИжСжТ) ГОжЗд)еРЗ ХНнНж еж гд ОШШ бЯб КбЯ ЗбЪгбнЙеРЗ гЗ нЮжбждГСнП Яб ЗбгЪбжгЗК ЗбКн дгбЯеЗ ЪдеГнд егїгЗ еРЗ ИНЮ ЗбМНнгїенЗ ИдЗЯб гЗ ЪбндЗ еж ЗбжХжб ббШСЭ ЗбВОС -гЗРЗї -</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Jer ko bi ikada mogaoda zavoli zver?Mali grad,to je tiho seoceSvaki dan kao prethodniMali grad, pun malih ljudiKoji se bude da bi rekliDobar dan!- Dobar dan!Dobar dan!- Dobar dan!Eno pekara sa posluћavnikomkao i uveknosi hleb i pecivoda proda.Svakog jutra isto,joљ od kada smo doљliU ovaj jadni provincijski gradiж.- Dobro jutro, Bel.Dobro jutro, gospodine.- Kuda ideљ?U biblioteku. Upravo sam proиitaladivnu priиu...o stabljici graљka i...- Baљ lepo.Mari!Hajde, poћuri!Evo иudne devojke,u to nema sumnje.Sva je smetena,zar ne vidite?Nema druљtva.- Ћivi u oblacima.Baљ je neobiиna devojka ta Bel.Dobar dan.- Dobar dan.Kako vam je porodica?Dobar dan.- Dobar dan.Kako je Vaљa ћena?Treba mi љest jaja!- To je preskupo!Valjda ima neљto viљeod provincijskog ћivota.O, Bel!- Dobro jutro.Vraжam pozajmljenu knjigu.- Proиitala si je?Nisam je ispuљtala iz ruke.Ima li neљto novo?</se>
  </para>
  <para id="2">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">lsn't this amazinglt's my favourite partBecause you'll seeHere's whereshe meets Prince CharmingBut she won 'tdiscover that it 's himTill chapter threeHey-hey !Hey-hey-hey !Now it's no wonderthat her name means beautyHer looks have go tNo parallelBut behind that fair facadeI'm afraid she's rather oddVery differentfrom the rest of usShe's nothing like the rest of usYes, different from the rest of usis BelleWow! You didn'tmiss a shot, Gaston!- You're the greatest hunterin the whole world!- I know .No beast alive standsa chance against you...- and no girl, for that matter.- It's true, Lefou.And I've got my sightsset on that one.- The inventor's daughter?- She's the one!- The lucky girl I'm going to marry.- But she--- The most beautiful girl in town.- I know, but--That makes her the best!- And don't I deserve the best?- Well, of course! I mean, you do!Right from the mom en twhen I met her, saw herRight from the mom en twhen I met her, saw herI said she's gorgeousAnd I fellHere in townthere's only sheWho is beautiful as meSo I'm making plansto woo and marry BelleLook, there he goeslsn't he dreamyMonsieur GastonOh, he's so cuteBe still my heartI'm hardly breathingHe 's such a tall, dark, strongand handsome brute- Bonjour- Good day- You call this bacon- What lovely grapes- Some cheese- Ten yards- Excuse me- I'll get the knife- Please let me thro ugh</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">енЗ нЗ СМЗбКЪбЮ ИеУСЪЙ ЗбЮШЗС КТПЗП нЗ СМбЕде ндШбЮ ИУСЪЙгС гд ОбЗбегЗРЗї -гС гд ОбЗбе -енЗЮЭ гЯЗдЯ(УГШбЮ ЪбнЯ ЗбдЗС нЗ (УЯжЭнбПГнд ЗбгСжНнЗК ж ЗбВОСждїЪЗПжЗ ббГСЦ бгбБ ЗбжЮжПЗббЪдЙ* G5™*-* G5™*....ббКСМгЙG-5-@hotmail.com-------------------------G-5-@hotmail.comDrooPee_@hotmail.comDrooPee_@hotmail.comG-5-@hotmail.comнЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЮЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬЬПгЗбЬЬЬЬеЬЬЬЬЬЬСжИ ЗбЬЬЬЬЬЯЬЬЬЬИЬЬЬЬнЬЬЬЬСЗбЬЬЬЬЬЬЬгЬЬЬЬЬЬжУЬЬЬЬг ЗбЬЬЛЬЬЬЗдЬЬЬнЗЗбЗбНЗбНбЗбНбЮЗбНбЮЙЗбНбЮЙ ЗЗбНбЮЙ ЗбЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбгЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбгШЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбгШЗЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбгШЗСЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбгШЗСПЗбНбЮЙ ЗбГжбмЗбгШЗСПЙУнПнжЯЗбЗК ЗбГдИЗБ ИЗбЗдКЩЗС</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Nema veze.Uzeжu ovu.Tu?! Ali proиitalasi je dvaput!Ta mi je omiljena.Daleka mesta...borbe maиevima, иarobne иinii preruљeni prinиevi.Ako ti se toliko sviрa,tvoja je.Ali, gospodine...- Insistiram!Hvala!Mnogo Vam hvala!Eno je, veoma je иudna.Pitam se da li se dobro oseжa.Uvek zagledana u daljinu.- A nos zabijen u knjigu.Bel je zagonetka za sve nas.Oh,zar nije to neverovatno?Ovo mi je omiljeni deo,zato љto, videжete,ovde sreжe svoga princa.Ali neжe otkriti da je to onsve do treжeg poglavlja.Nije иudo љto jojime znaиi lepotica.Po lepoti jojniko ravan nije.Ali iza te neћne fasade,ona je priliиno иudna.Drugaиija od nas.Nimalo nalik na nas.Ona je drugaиija od nas,ta Bel!Nikad ne promaљiљ,Gastone!Ti si najbolji lovac nacelom svetu! -Znam.Nijedna zver nemaљanse kod tebe.A isto tako ni devojka.- Tako je, Lefu.A ja sam se namerio na onu.Pronalazaиevu жerku?- Ona jesreжnica koju жu da oћenim.- Ali, ona je...Najlepљa u gradu.- Znam, ali...Zato je najbolja.A zar ja ne zasluћujem najbolje?- Naravno, ali...</se>
  </para>
  <para id="3">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">There must be more thanthis provincial lifeJust watch, I'm goingto make Belle my wifeLook, there she goes, a girlwho's strange but specialA most peculiarmademoiselleIt's a pity and a sinShe doesn't quite fit in'Ca use she really isa funny girlA beauty but a funny girlShe really is a funny girlThat Belle- Hello, Belle.- Bonjour, Gaston.Gaston, may I havemy book, please?How can you read this?There's no pictures!Well, some peopleuse their imagination.Belle, it's about time you gotyour head out of those books...and paid attentionto more important things.Like me.The whole town'stalking about it.It's not rightfor a woman to read.Soon she start sgetting ideas and thinking.- Gaston, you are positively primeval.- Why, thank you, Belle.What do you say you and metake a walk over to the tavern...- and take a look at my trophies?- Maybe some other time.- What's wrong with her?- She's crazy.- He's gorgeous!Please, Gaston, I can't.I have to get home to help my father.Goodbye.That crazy old loon!He needs all the help he can get.Don't talk aboutmy father that way !Yeah! Don't talk abouther father that way !My father is not crazy .He's a genius!- Papa?- How on earth did that happen?- Doggone it!- Are you all right, Papa?I-I'm a-- I'm about readyto give up on this hunk of junk.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">Ед ГгЯддн(ЮЗКб (ЕИСЗеЗг бндЯжбдЗЛдЗ ЪФС нжгеРЗ гЗ ЗУКЫСЮе ЗбЮИЦ ЪбнеЭн гРЯСЗКе ИКбЯ ЗбЭКСЙ ЯКИ ГдЗбЩб ЯЗд ХПнЮеж Зббнб ЯЗд ЕШЗСеЗЪКСЭ Гд ЗбЗЦШСЗИ ЗбРнПЭЪ ЗбгМСгбЗСКЯЗИ ЗбМСнгЙ ЗбГжбм нКЦЗЪЭнТнП ЗбеСжИ гд НМгеИГХжЗК ЗбЯбЗИ Эн ГЛСенХИН ЗбОжЭ жУжУЙж ККНжб ЗбжУжУЙ Ебм ебжУЙГдЗ ГРЯС еРЗбГде ИЪП гЖЙ ж ГСИЪнд ЪЗгЗрбг нКЫнС ЪЮб ЗбеЗСИ ГИПЗрбЗТЗб ЗбеЗСИ ЕдУЗдЗрбЗТЗб ОЗЖЭЗрж бд нНжб ФнЖЗр Инде ж Инд гНЗжбКе ббеСИбНУд НЩдЗИндгЗ ЭСЗЖУдЗ ККгКЪ ИЗбЩб ж Зббнб НбнЭнд бегбПндЗ гЗ еж ГЪЩгЗбКбЭЗТГФМЪ Яб гд нФЗеПЯб гд Эн еРе ЗбИбЗПГд нбЮн дЩСЙ Ъбм КбЯ ЗбжМжееДбЗБ ЗбСМЗб(ег ГЯЛС ЛгЗднЙ гШбжИжд Эн (ГгСнЯЗЩддКн ПСУК еРЗ МнПЗрГСГнК Яб гд ОбЭдЗїЗбНб еж Гдег ОбЭдЗж дНд едЗдЪгЎ ж Ебм гКм УнУКгС РбЯїдЪгЎ ОЗХЙр Где бнУК бПндЗ ГнЙ СЯжИЙИЭЦб ШЗЖСЙ (ГИСжКТн) ЗбКн ЗОКЭК ЭМГЙбг КЯд бКСЯИ еРе ЗбШЗЖСЙ нЗ ГОнж бЗ КЩддн бЗ ГЪбг(Ебм Гнд УКРеИ ГнЦЗр нЗ (УЯжЭнбПЕбм Гнд УГРеИїбЗ ГЪбгнжКЗе)ї)гКм ЯдК УКОИСдЗ ИЗбдЮжП нЗ СМбїГн дЮжПї(ОгУЙ гбЗннд ТСЪеЗ (жнУКгжСбЗдП(ИЗбХНСЗБ Эн (нжКЗеГдК бЗ КЭег Ъг ККНПЛ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">njena me lepotaoborila s nogu.U ovom gradiжu samo je onalepa kao ja.Zato planiram daosvojim i oћenim Bel.Eno ga, ide.Zar nije kao san?Gospodin Gaston...Oh, tako je sladak.Miruj, srce moje,jedva diљem.On je tako visok, tamnokos,snaћan i zgodan.Dobar dan.To riba?- Prelepo groћрe.Deset jardi.Idem po noћ.- Pustite da proрem!Hleb i riba nisu sveћi.- Greљite.Valjda ima neљto viљeod provincijskog ћivota!Samo gledajte,Bel жe postati moja ћena!Gle, eno je,иudna i posebna.Zaista neobiиna gospoрica.Љteta je i grehљto se ne uklapa.Ali zaista je neobiиna.Lepa, ali neobiиna.Ona je zaista neobiиna!Ta Bel.Zdravo, Bel.- Zdravo, Gaston.Gaston, vrati mi knjigu.Kako moћeљ da иitaљ ovo?Nema slika!Neki ljudi koriste maљtu.Bel, vreme je da izvuиeљglavu iz knjigai obratiљ paћnju navaћnije stvari.Kao љto sam ja.Ceo grad bruji o tome.Nije u redu da ћensko иita.Onda poиinje i darazmiљlja.Gastone, stvarno si zadrt.- Hvala, Bel.Љta kaћeљ da proљetamodo taverne,da pogledamo moje trofeje?- Drugi put.Љta je sa njom?- On je boћanstven!Ne mogu, Gastone. Moram dapomognem ocu.Zdravo!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="4">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">I'll never get thisBone headed contraption to work!Yes, you will, and you'll winfirst prize at the fair tomorrow .- Hmph!- And become a world-famous inventor.- You really believe that?- I always have .Well, what are we waitin' for?I'll have this thing fixed in no time.Hand me that-- the-- the--the dog-legged clincher there .So, did you have a good timein town today ?I got a new book.Papa, do you think I'm odd?My daughter? Odd?Where would you getan idea like that?Oh, I don't know. It's just thatI'm not sure I fit in here .There's no one I can really talk to.What about that Gaston?H-He's a handsome fella.He's handsome, all right,and rude and conceited and--- Oh, Papa, he's not for me.- Well, don't you worry...'cause this invention's gonna bethe start of a new life for us.I think that's done it.Now, let's give it a try.- It works !- It does?- It does!- You did it!You really did it!Hitch up Philippe, girl.I'm off to the fair!Goodbye, Papa.Good luck!Goodbye, Belle.Take care while I'm gone.We should be there by now .We should be there by now .Maybe we missed a turn.I guess I should've taken--Wait a minute.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">ЗдКЩСГн дЮжПїГнеЗ ЗбгПнСїбЗТЗб ЗбжЮК гИЯСЗр Ъбм КПОб ЗбгИЗНЛ ЗбЭнПСЗбнЙГбЗ КЩд РбЯїГдЗ ГЭегбЗТЗб еРЗ КНЮнЮЯбЯд ИгМСП Гд нЪИС ЗбгМСгжд НПжП ЗбжбЗнЙУКХИН гУГбЙ ЭнПСЗбнЙНУдЗрЎ бд нНПЛ еРЗГКгдм Гд КЯжд Ъбм НЮбеРЗ ЯдК УГЮКСН Гд дОКСЮГн УнЗУЙ КЪЗжд Инд ЗбжЯЗбЗК гдР ЗбИПЗнЙФЭЗЭнЙ КЗгЙИЗбКГЯнПМнПСИгЗ нгЯдЯ ГК КНПЛдн Ъд(ПЯКжСЙ (КЗдЯСнПнбЗ нжМП гЗ ГЮжбНУИ гЗ УгЪКСИгЗ КЯжд УЗЪПК ЗбеЗСИндЭКНК ЗбИЗИ ЗбРнУгН бег ИЗбОСжМЯгЗ ЮбКбЗ нжМП гЗ ГЮжбГдК бЗ ККИЪ гИПГ ЗбФЭЗЭнЙ ГнеЗ ЗбгПнСЗУгЪЎ ГдЗ бЗ ГКНПЛ Ъд гжЩЭнСИгЗ нМИ ЪбнЯбГдеЗ ЮП КЯжд гЭКЗН Яб ФЖнМИ Гд дКНПЛ гЪеЗ(ЗбВд нЗ УнП (гЗеждбд ККНПЛ гЪ ГНПЯнЭ дИбнїЗбГдЗИнИ КгбГ МУПеЗ ИЗбгЗБдЪШнеЗ гНбжб ЗбдЗбжЯУжддХЭ гббнМСЗг ИЗбУЗЪЙгЗ еж ГгбеЗ ИЗбдМЗЙ Эн СГнЯїНУдЗрЎ ЭЪбдЗ Яб гЗ ИжУЪдЗж ЗбИЮнЙ ЪбнеЗЕгЗ Гд КЮЗжг ЭКЪнФГж КУКУбг ЭКгжК</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Ne govori tako o mom ocu!Da, ne govori tako o njenom ocu!Moj otac nije lud.On je genije.Tata?- Kako se ovo dogodilo?Bestraga.- Jesi li dobro, tata?Ja жu... Spreman sam daostavim ovo smeжe.Uvek tako kaћeљ.- Sada tako i mislim.Nikada ovo иudoneжe da proradi!Hoжe. I sutra жeљ osvojitiprvu nagradu na sajmu.I postaжeљ svetski poznatpronalazaи.Stvarno verujeљ u to?- Oduvek sam verovala.Љta onda иekamo?Srediжu ga zaиas!Dodaj mi taj prokleti alat!Jesi li se lepo provela u gradu?Dobila sam novu knjigu.Tata, da li misliљ da sam иudna?Moja kжi иudna?!Otkud ti takva ideja?Ne znam. Nisam sigurnada se uklapam ovde.Nemam s kimeda popriиam.A onaj Gaston?On je zgodan mladiж.Da, zgodan je,ali neotesan i uobraћen i...Nije on za mene.- Ne brini se.Ovim izumom жemo dazapoиnemo novi ћivot.Mislim da je gotov.Hajde da ga isprobamo.Radi!- Da?Radi!- Uspeo si!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="5">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Come on, Philippe, it's a short cut.We'll be there in no time.This can't be right.Where have you taken us, Philippe?We better turn around.Whoa. Whoa, boy .Whoa, now, whoa, Philippe.Oh! Oh!Look out! No!Oh! Oh!Look out! No!Whoa!Whoa, boy !Back up, back up, back up!Good boy! Good boy .That's good, that's-- Back up!Steady, steady, now .Steady.Steady. No, Philippe!Philippe?Oh.Help!Is-- Is someone there ?Help!Oh!</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">ЗЭЪб гЗ КНКЗМе нЗ СМб...жнЗ ЭКмЕд ЗКХбК ИЗбФСШЙ...УГЫСТ еРе ЭнЪндЯФЯСЗр бЯгедПУ ЕдФЗЖнХНнНїбнУ ЗбджЪЗбРн ККжЮЪ жМжП Яб еРЗ ЗбНИС Ъбм МУПебнУ еРЗ ЗбджЪ ГИПЗргЗ ЗбТгд ЗбКЮСнИн бСУг Яб еРЗїгЖЙ УЗЪЙГж гЖКЗдбЗ ИП Гд гд СУг бе еРЗ ЗбжФгЮЦм ЗбЯЛнС гд ЗбжЮКУГЪСЭ гд еж(УнП (ИнбнЯбЗ ККНПЛ гЪнНУдЗрЎ бЯд еРЗ УнХЪИ ЗбКЪЗжд ИнддЗЗбКЪЗждїГдЗ ГЦЪ СМЗбн Эн ОШСж ГдК КЪШн гДКгСЗК ХНЭнЙЗбХНЗЭЙ гМСП ГПЗЙУКЪнП еДбЗБ ЗбСМЗб ГУСЪ гд ЗбЯбЗИ ЗбИжбнУнЙбЗ дНКЗМЯдНд дКЮЭм ВЛСегж УдгУЯ Иег Ъг ЮСнИЗбгФЯбЙ ЗбКн ГМПеЗ Эн КЮЭн ЗбГЛСен ГдЯ КЯжд ОбЭ ЗбЭСнУЙ ПЗЖгЗрУдСм еРЗ(ИбЗЯЭжК)Ў (гждКЗдЗ)бУК гУбНЗрЪд ЕРдЯЭГдЗ бЗ ГЛЮ ИГНП ЗбВдГДЯП бЯц нЗ ЗгСГЙГдЗ бЗ ГФЯб ГПдм ОШСж гОПС ЗбИнСУжЯнК нДЯП РбЯМнПЎ бд КгЗдЪ ЕРЗр Ед ЗбКЮШК ХжСЙбКОбнПеЗ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Osedlaj konja.Odoh na sajam!Zdravo, tata. Sreжno!Zdravo, Bel!Иuvaj se dok nisam tu!Trebalo je da veж stignemo.Moћda smo negdepogreљno skrenuli.Trebalo je da...Иekaj malo.Ne. Idemo ovuda.Hajde, Filipe!|To je preиica!Stiжi жemo zaиas!Ovo nije u redu.Gde si nas to doveo Filipe?Bolje da se okrenemo.Opla...Pazi!Pazi!Opa!Natrag, natrag!Dobar deиko!Dobro je... Natrag!Miran!Ne, Filipe, ne!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="6">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Hello?Hello!Poor fellow must havelost his way in the woods.Keep quiet.Maybe he'll go away .Is someone there ?Not a word, Lumiere .Not one word !I-I don't mean to intrude,but I've lost my horse...and-- and I need a placeto stay for the night.Oh, Cogs worth, have a heart .Shh!O-O-Ow! Ow! Ow!Of course, monsieur,you are welcome here .Who said that?Over here .- Where ?- Hello.Incredible!Well, now you've done it, Lumiere .Splendid! Just peachy !- How is this accomplished?- Put me down at once!Stop that! Hee-hee-hee.Stop that, I say !Sir, close that at once!- Do you mind?- I-I beg your pardon?It's-- It's just that I'venever seen a clock that--Oh, you are soakedto the bone, monsieur.Come.Warm yourself by the fire.- Thank you.- No, no, no!You know what the master will doif he finds him here .I demand that you stopright there !Oh, no, no!Not the master's chair!Oh, no, no!Not the master's chair!I'm not seeing this!I'm not seeing this!Well, hello there, boy .- Oh, what service!- All right!This has gone far enough.I'm in charge here--</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">бЗ КеКг Гд едЗЯ гд УнЪПгбЮКбЯ ж ГдК КМбУ едЗбУК гд ЗОКЗС (бндЯжбд ИжСжТ) бнКбЮм ЗбЦСИЙгд ЭЪбїГОКЯЎ СЖнУЙ ЗбМгежСнЙїГдКц бЗ КЭегндГдЗ УМнд ИЯб еРЗенЗЯЗд нгЯдЯ Гд КРеИ ббФСШЙЯЗд нгЯдЯ Гд Кден КбЯЗбгУГбЙ ЮИб Гд КИПГ НКмбЗЎ ГдЗ УМнд НЮЗрж ГдКц ЯРбЯ ГнЦЗр ЗбВдбНЩЙ ЕЫбЗЮЯ ббИЗИ ОбЭЯГбг КФЪСн ИЗбЭЦжб ГИПЗрЪдПгЗ бг КМПн ГнЙ НСЗУЙ ИЗбОЗСМїЗбИЗИ бЗ нЭКН Ужм гд ЗбОЗСМУгЯ ЗбТМЗМ ИжХКЗдж гЦЗП ббСХЗХбЗ ОСжМ гд едЗ нЗ ЗгСГЙнМИ Гд дКОбХ гдег ЗбВдбЗ нгЯд(нЪСЭжд ИГгС (нжКЗееРЗ ГПЪм Гд дКОбХ гдегЕд ГгУЯК Иег ЗбФСШЙ ЭУнЪСЭждЕбм Гнд УдРеИнМИ Гд дНСХ Ъбм Гд нФЯбжЗ Гн ОШС(НКм дХб бЬ(нжКЗебдЭЪб гЗ ЪбндЗГКЩддЗ УдМП ЗбдЮжП едЗЯ НЮЗрїСИгЗ бг нЯд (КФЗСбТ) ХЗПЮЗр КгЗгЗр...бЯд ИЗбдеЗнЙИЗбдеЗнЙ бд нжМП УИИ ббЯРИГСм Где НЗбгЗ дНХб ЪбнеЗдЪИС ИеЗ ббгЯУнЯдУКЮб ЪПЙ НЗЭбЗК гд ЗбПСМЙ ЗбЛЗгнЙ(НКм дХб Ебм (ИЗдЗгЗГдК гЪМИ ЭЪбЗр ИгКМС ГПжЗК ЗбЫШУ еРЗХНнНїдЪгбЗ ГгЗдЪ ЗбВд ПЮ ЗбгУЗгнСИЗбГПжЗК ЗбОФИнЙбЪФС Гж ЪФСнд УдЙ ЮЗПгЙдХЭ ЗбИбЗП КШЗСПдЗ(бд дХб бЬ(ИЗдЗгЗ) Гж (нжКЗебнУ Пжд гУЗЪПЙ(бЗ нгЯд Гд КУЗЪПдЗ (ЭнСжднЯЗЯнЭ КЮжб еРЗї..бнУ гЪдЗ дЮжП Гж гбЗИУЪдПн Яб еРЗЩддК ЗбОШЙ ЯЗдК КЪКгП(Ъбм ШЗЖСЙ (ГИСжКТн</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Jao!Upomoж! Ima li koga?Upomoж!Ima li koga?Jadnik se sigurnoizgubio u љumi.Tiho. Moћda ode.Ima li koga?Ni reиi, Lumije!Ne ћelim da smetam,ali ostao sam bez konja...i treba mi prenoжiљte.Kogsvorte, imaj srca.Pa naravno, gospodine,dobrodoљli!Ko je to rekao?Ovamo.Gde?- Zdravo!Neverovatno!Eto ti sad, Lumije.Odliиno! Naprosto sjajno.Kako je ovo uspelo?- Spusti me! Smesta!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="7">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">No! No tea. No tea!His mustache tickles, Mama!Oh! Hello!Uh-oh.There's a stranger here.Master, allow me to explain.The gentleman was lost in the woods.He was cold and wet, so--Master, I'd like to takethis moment to say...I was against this from the start .It was all his fault.I tried to stop them.Would they listen to me? No, no--Who are you?What are you doing here ?I-I-I was lost in the woods and--- You are not welcome here !- I-I-I'm sorry.- What are you staring at?- N-Nothing.So, you've come to stareat the beast, have you?Please, I meant no harm!I-I just needed a place to stay .- I'll give you a place to stay !- No, no, please! No! No!Oh, boy. Belle's gonna getthe surprise of her life, huh, Gaston?Yep, this is her lucky day .I'd like to thank you allfor coming to my wedding.First I better go in thereand propose to the girl.And you, Lefou, now, whenBelle and I come out that door- -Oh, I know! I know !I-I strike up the band!- Not yet!- Sorry.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">...бПндЗ ЕРЗрЯб гЗ дНКЗМГндїгОТд"СЗнИ КФЗдУ жжПТ"УЯжЭнбП) еж гд Хгг ЗбжФг бЗ ГдКцї)ГНЦС ЗбСУг Ябе гЪеЯб ЪдХСГЪднЎ ЗдЩС Ебне(нФИе ЯднУЙ (УнУКндЯдК ГЪбг Где гедПУ Гж гЗ ФЗИебЯдЎ нЗ ббежбгжеИКе ИЗбЭд СенИЙгЗРЗ ГнЦЗрїгЗ СГнЯ Ие ЯЕдУЗдїЯЗд бШнЭЗрбЯд ЯЗд ЫЗнЙ Эн ЗбПЮЙЯб ФЖ нМИ Гд нЯжд гЛЗбнЗрИЗбЦИШ ЯгЗ СУгеИПГК ГФЪС Гд ЗбгУГбЙ ЯбеЗгМСП гТНЙж ЗбКн ЯЗд нЪнФ ИеЗгЪдЗ СЮгЯХНнНїдЪгЮП ГКХб ИЯ ЛЗднЙрФЯСЗр(Эжбн)гЗ ЗУг ЗбШСнЮ ЗбШжнбЗбРн ГОРдЗ Эн ШСнЮдЗ ббУМдї(ГЩде ЯЗд ФЗСЪ (ЕдМбнФж ГгЗг ЗбУМдЗбФЗСЪЗд ЗбгКЮЗШЪЗдїЭнКТ) ж (ИнСУн)Ў бгЗРЗї)ФЯСЗр бЯцЗУКЪПжЗ -Ебм Гнд УдРеИї -НнЛ нгЯддЗ Гд дден ПжСдЗ ЯУМдЗБж дХИН гПднндбгЗРЗ бЗ КЯЭ Ъд КбЯ ЗбГбЫЗТ ГнеЗ ЗбЭКм ЗбГИнЦж КОИСдЗ гИЗФСЙрЗХгКжЗгЗРЗїгСНИЗрГебЗрнЗ ЭКЗЙгЗРЗ КЭЪбждї...НУдЗрдНд дХШЗППжд УдЗСЗКїдНИ Гд дХШЗП ИГнПндЗ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Gospodine,smesta to zatvorite.Hoжete?- Izvinite.Izvinite, ali nikadanisam video sat...Mokri ste do gole koћe.Doрite, ugrejte se pored vatre.Hvala.- Ne, ne!Znaљ љta жe gospodarda uradi ako ga naрe ovde.Zahtevam da smesta staneљ!Ne, ne! Ne u gospodarevu fotelju.Ovo se ne deљava!Ovo se ne deљava!Zdravo, momиe!Kakva usluga!- Dobro.Prevrљio si svaku meru!Ja sam ovde glavni...Jeste li za љoljicu toplogиaja? Ugrejaжe Vas.Ne! Ne иaj!Ne иaj!Njegovi brkovi golicaju, mama!Zdravo!Ovde je stranac.Gospodaru, dopustite da objasnim.Gospodin se izgubio u љumi.Hladno mu je i mokar je...Gospodaru, hteo bih da iskoristim ovajtrenutak da Vam kaћem...Ja sam bio protiv!On je kriv za sve.Pokuљao sam da ga zaustavimali on nije hteo da sluљa...Ko si ti? Љta radiљ ovde?Izgubio sam se u љumi i...Nisi dobrodoљao ovde!- Izvinite.</se>
  </para>
  <para id="8">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Gaston,what a pleasant surprise.Isn't it, though?I'm just full of surprises.You know, Belle,there's not a girl in town whowouldn't love to be in your shoes.This is the day--This is the dayyour dreams come true.This is the dayyour dreams come true.What do you knowabout my dreams, Gaston?Plenty !Here. Picture this.A rustic hunting lodge,my latest kill roasting on the fire...and my little wifemassaging my feet...while the little onesplay on the floor with the dogs.- We'll have six or seven.- Dogs?No, Belle.- Strapping boys like me.- Imagine that.- Do you know who thatlittle wife will be?- Let me think.- You, Belle.- Gaston, I'm--I'm speechless.I really don't knowwhat to say .- Say you'll marry me.- I'm very sorry, Gaston, but--but I just don't deserve you!So, how'd it go?I'll have Belle for my wife .Make no mistake about that.Touchy !Is he gone?Can you imagine?He asked me to marry him.Me, the wife of thatboorish, brainless--Madame GastonCan't you just see itMadame Gastonhis little wifeNo, sir, not meI guaran tee it</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">ЗбХнП ИЗбнП...ГЩд Гд ЗбУДЗб ежгЗРЗ КЭЪбнд ГдКц едЗїГХШЗП -(МСЗнУн) -(ЗИКЪПн нЗ (МСЗнУнКСЗМЪн(ГдК ЗбеЗСИжд гд деС (ЭжЯУбЗ ККНСЯжЗ ж бж ЮнП ГдгбЙЗИКЪПжЗ ЪдеЗЗИКЪПжЗ ЪдеЗНУдЗрЎ НУдЗрЗеПГ ЭНУИУнПнЗИЮ гЯЗдЯЦЪ УбЗНЯ ГСЦЗрПЪеЗ ЗбВд -ЗбВд -ПЪеЗМжд)Ў ЗКСЯ ЗбЭКЗЙ) -ЗХгК -Мжд)Ў ЗКСЯ ЗбЭКЗЙ) -ЦЪе ГСЦЗр -ЗКСЯ ЗбУбЗНЦЪ ЗбУбЗН ГСЦЗр -(Мжд) -ЗКСЯе ЗбВдЦЪ ЗбУбЗН ГСЦЗржЗНПУГЦЫШ ЗбТдЗПЗЛдЗдГНУдКЗНЦС ЗбУбЗНГНЦСе..ЕнЗЯ Гд КДРнеЗГдКУКЯжднд ИОнСНУдЗрїЗРеИн бжЗбПЯбд ГЮжб ФнЖЗр бГн ФОХ нЗ СМбЗеПГ Эбд дДРнЯГнд УнЗСКЯї -Ъбм ЗбШСнЮ -ГСнП гЭЗКнНЯнгЯдег Гд нЭЪбжЗ ИЯц гЗ нСнПжд бЗдКТЗЪ ЗбгЪбжгЗККЪбгнд еРЗЎХНнНїбЗ ГЪСЭ Ужм ЗбЮбнбЭКНК ИЗИ ЗбЪнЗПЙ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Znaиi, doљao si dabuljiљ u zver?Nisam mislio niљta loљe.Samo mi je trebalo prenoжiљte.Daжu ti ja prenoжiљte.- Molim vas, nemojte...Bel жe se iznenaditikao nikada, a Gaston?Da. Danas je njensreжan dan.Hvala svima koji sudoљli na moje venиanje.Ali prvo da uрem izaprosim devojku.Lefu, kad Bel i ja izaрemo...Znam, znam.Raspalimo muziku!Ne joљ!- Izvini.Gastone, kakvo prijatnoiznenaрenje!Zar ne, Bel?Pun sam iznenaрenja.Znaљ Bel, nema devojke u gradu kojane bi volela da bude na tvom mestu.Danas je dan...kada жe se svitvoji snovi ostvariti.Љta ti znaљ o mojimsnovima, Gastone?Mnogo toga. Zamisli ovo.Mala lovaиka kuжa,moj ulov se peиe na vatrici...a ћenica mi masira stopala...dok se maliљani igrajusa kuиiжima.Imaжemo bar љest, sedam.- Pasa?Ne, Bel.Deиaka snaћnih kao ja!- Ma, zamisli samo.Znaљ li ko жe mi biti ћenica?- Da razmislim.Ti, Bel!- Gaston, ja...Nemam reиi.Ne znam љta da kaћem.Reci da иeљ se udati za mene.- Ћao mi je Gaston, ali...</se>
  </para>
  <para id="9">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">I want much more thanthis provincial lifeI want adventurein the great wide somewhereI want it morethan I can tellAnd for onceit might be grandTo have someone understandI want so much morethan they've got plannedPhilippe! What are youdoing here? Where's--Philippe! What are youdoing here? Where's--Where's Papa? Where is he, Philippe?What happened?Oh, we have to find him.You have to take me to him.What is this place?Philippe, please, steady.Steady.Papa!Couldn't keep quiet,could we?Just had to invite him to stay ,didn't we?Serve him tea,sit in the master's chair.- Pet the pooch!- I was trying to be hospitable.Hello?Is anyone here?Hello?Papa? Papa?Are you here?Mama, there's a girlin the castle.Now, Chip, I'll not have youmaking up such wild stories.Really, Mama.I saw her.- Not another word. Into the tub.- But-- What--A girl!I saw a girl in the castle!</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">Гбг КЭЪбнїбг ГЭЪбГгЗСУК ЪбЗЮЙ МдУнЙ гЪ (УЯжЭнбП)їбЗбЯд ЯдК КНИндеОСМ гЪе УИЪЙ ВОСждгдїВУЭ нЗ УнПнЕде нжг ЗбУИКдНд Эн ГМЗТЙНУдЗрЎ еРЗ еж ЗбгШбжИгЪРСЙр нЗ УнПнїЭЯгЗ КСмУГНКЗМ ИЪЦ ЗбЪгбж ГСнПе Гд нКг Эн УСнЙВУЭЎ КЮжб ГдЯ КНКЗМ ИЪЦ ЗбЪгбїеРе ЪнЗПЙ ШИнЙХНнНїИЗбКГЯнП нЗ УнПнбЯд ббНнжЗдЗКнЗ ЕбенгЗРЗ НПЛ бЯїКНКЗМ бЪдЗнЙ ШИнЙЗУгЪ нЗ УнПн -ЗдКЩС -УГКХб ИЗбЕУЪЗЭбд ККХб ИГНП нЗ ПЯКжСНУдЗреРЗ ХНнНгЗ..гЗРЗ КСнПїГКЪбгїЯЭмЎ ГСнП еРЗ ЗбгОИжб ОЗСМ ЗбУнЗСЙ нЗ СМбЯЗдК ЭКЗЙ ХЫнСЙГбнУ бЯ ЮбИїнЗ ЕбенЪдПн ЗИдЙЪдПн ЭКЗЙ ХЫнСЙж ГдЗ ГнЦЗрбЯд Ед бг ГЯдЭЪбК гЗ ЯЗд ЪбншугЗ ЯдЗ Эн ШСнЮдЗ Ебнед ЗбВдХНнНїКНСЯ ббнгндЗдКЩСЕбм Гнд УдРеИї(ГжТжнМж)еРЗ ИЗбЫСИ нЗ СМбнМИ Гд дРеИ ббФСЮ(ЪЗЖбКн Эн (ФнЯЗЫжж КЩд ЗбФСШЙ бЗ КЪбг РбЯїКЩдег бд нЯжджЗ едЗЯ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">I, kako je bilo?Bel жe mi biti ћena.Upamti to.Dirljivo.Je l' otiљao?Zamislite, zaprosio me je.Ja da budem ћena tompraznoglavom grubijanu!?Gospoрa Gaston?Zamislite to!Gospoрa Gaston, njegova ћenica.Ne ja. To vam garantujem.Ja ћelim mnogo viљeod ovog provincijskog ћivota!Ћelim avanturuna nekom prostranstvu!Ћelim to viљe nego љtomogu da kaћem!Kako bih bila zahvalna,da imam nekog kome razume.Ћelim mnogo viљe od onoga љto suza mene isplanirali.Filipe, љta radiљ tu?Gde je...tata, Filipe? Gde je?Љta se desilo?Moramo ga pronaжi!Odvedi me do njega.Kakvo je ovo mesto?Filipe, molim te, smiri se.Miran!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="10">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Irresponsible, devil-may-care ,waxy eared, slack-jawed--Papa?Did you see that?- It's a girl!- I know it's a girl.Don't you see? She's the one!The girl we have been waiting for!- She has come to break the spell!- Wait a minute! Wait a minute!Papa?Papa?Hello?Is someone here?Wait!I'm looking for my father. I--That's funny.I'm sure there was someone.I-Is anyone here?- Belle?- Papa!- H-H-How did you find me?- Oh, your hands are like ice.- We have to get you out of there.- Belle, I want you to leave this place.- Who's done this to you?- No time to explain.- You must go. Now!- I won't leave you.- What are you doing here?- Run, Belle!- Who's there? Who are you?- The master of this castle.I've come for my father.Please let him out.-Can't you see he's sick?-Then he shouldn't have trespassed here!But he could die.Please, I'll do anything.There's nothing you can do.He's my prisoner.Oh, there must be some wayI can-- Wait!- Take me instead.- You?You would take his place?Belle, no! You don't knowwhat you're doing!If I did,would you let him go?Yes, but you must promiseto stay here forever.Come into the light.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">гЗРЗ ИЯїгЗРЗ Ъд (днжнжСЯ)їгЗРЗ ЪдеЗїНИнИКн НЗгб нЗ ГОнКЭег Гд ЗбНИ еж дЮШЙ ЦЪЭЯ ЗбВдж ег нЪбгжд РбЯбЗ нЪдн еРЗ ГбЗ КРеИбЯд нМИ Гд ККХСЭ ИРЯЗБ(дРеИ бЬ(ГжТжнМжбг КЯд (ГжТжнМж) Эн ШСнЮдЗ ГнеЗ ЗбГИнЦ(бнУ Збгег Гнд КжМП (ГжТжнМжИб гЗ нжМП ИеЗГнеЗ ЗбЮЗЖПКЪЗгбЗК (УЯжЭнбП) ИИШЗЮЙ ЗбЗЖКгЗд ЗдКеК гдР Тгд(ГдЭЮ дЮжПЗр ЯЛнСЙ ИгЮЗШЪЙ (жнбЮИб Гд нКг НИУеїИЗбЦИШ -(ЯЗд гд (ФнЯЗЫж -(бгЗРЗ нГКн СМб гд (ФнЯЗЫжЕбм едЗж ндЭЮ ЛгЗд ВбЗЭ ИЯб КбЯ ЗбГгЗЯдЭн ГЮб гд ФеСїЫУнб УнЗСЙЎ ИСнП ХжКнКОТндЎ ЗУКМЖЗС УнЗСЙГСУдЗ гд нИНЛжд ИеРЗ ЗбГгС -МнП -гЗРЗ Ъд ЗбЦИЗШ ЗбЭнПСЗбнндїгЗРЗ дЮжб бегїгЗРЗ КЩдї -(ГнеЗ ЗбЮЗЖП (ИнбнЯ -бПндЗ ФЖЮЗИб ХнЗП гд (КЗгЗСЗЯ) ОгУЙ гд ЗбгУЗМндЯЗд (УЯжЭнбП) нЪнФ едЗ ЕРЗрїдЪгЎ НКм Кг НИУе гдР ФеСндгЗКК Ггеж ЗОКЭм жЗбПебнУ бе Эн ЗбПднЗ Ужм ГОнебРЗ ЭнОШШж нМеТ бгДЗгСКе бГФеСНКм нХб бЯб ФЖЯб ЪдХСЛг нПгС ЗбГПбЙ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Nismo mogli da жutimo, je l' da?Morali smo da ga pozovemoda ostane.Posluћili mu иaj, poseli gau gospodarevu fotelju.Hteo sam da budem gostoprimljiv.Hej, ima li koga?Hej!Tata? Tata?Jesi li tu?Mama, u dvorcu jeneka devojka.Иip, ne smeљ da izmiљljaљtakve gluposti.Stvarno, mama.Video sam je!Ni reиi viљe.U vodu.Videla sam devojku u dvorcu!Ne rekoh li?Neodgovoran, nepaћljiv,neposluљan i lajav...Tata?Jesi li video to?To je devojka!- Znam da je to devojka.Zar ne shvataљ?To je ta. Devojka koju иekamo!Doљla je da skine иini.- Иekaj malo! Иekaj malo!Tata.Tata?Ima li koga?Иekajte, traћim oca. Ja...Иudno. Sigurna samda sam je bio neko.Ima li koga?Bel?- Tata!Kako si me naљla?- Ruke su ti kao led.Moramo da te izvuиemo odavde.Bel, hoжu da odeљ.Ko ti je ovo uradio?- Nema vremena za objaљnjenje.Moraљ da odeљ!- Neжu da te ostavim!Љta radiљ tu?- Beћi, Bel!Ko je to? Ko ste Vi?- Gospodar ovog dvorca.Doљla sam po oca.Molim vas, pustite ga.Zar ne vidite da je bolestan?- Nije trebalo da dolazi ovamo!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="11">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">- You have my word.- Done!No, Belle, listen to me.I'm old. I've lived my life.- Wait!- Belle!- Wait!No! Please spare my daughter.Please!She's no longer your concern.Take him to the village.Let me out.Please let me out!Let me out!Please! Please!- Master?- What?Uh, since the girl is going to bewith us for quite some time...I was thinking that you might wantto offer her a more comfortable room.Then again, maybe not.You didn't even let mesay goodbye.I'll never see him again.- I didn't get to say goodbye.- I'll show you to your room.My room?But I thought--- You wanna-- You wannastay in the tower?- No.Then follow me.- Say something to her.- Huh? Oh.I, uh, hope you like it here .The castle is your home now ,so you can go anywhere you likeexcept the west wing.- What's in the west--- It's forbidden!Now, if you need anything,my servants will attend you.Dinner. Invite her to dinner.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">бд КжМП ФИЯЙ ббЗКХЗбдНд Эн гдШЮЙ гдЪТбЙбЗ КжМП ГИСЗМ СЮгнЙ едЗЭн (гждКЗдЗ) ЗбЫСИнЙбг бЗ КХгК нЗ (КнСЗдУ)їГНЗжб ЭЮШ Гд ГжЭС ЪбнЯ МежПЯеДбЗБ ЗбдЗУ ЯЗбФИЯЙЯбгЗ ЗТПЗПК гЮЗжгКЯЯбгЗ ЗТПЗП ЗбГгС УжБЗрнИПж бн Гд едЗЯМИЗд нНЗжб Гд нИСС гжЮЭеЕд ИЮнК ОЗСМ ЗбГгС ж ЗбКТгК ЗбХгКГЩб НнЗреРЗ гЗ ЮЗбжееРЗ гЗ ГОИСждн Иеж ГдК гУКЪП ббЪнФ еЯРЗЭн гЯЗд гЫбЮ ЯЗбУМдИндгЗ ЗбГгжС гдЮбИЙ ИЗбОЗСМїНгЗнЙ ЗбдЭУ ПЗЭЪ Южнж ЯРбЯ ЗбНЮнЮЙЕнЗЯцнЗ ЗгСГЙЕнЗЯцЯнЭ НЗбЯ нЗ СМбїГдЗ ОЗЖЭ МПЗреРЗ Нж НЗбнГОРжЗ УнЗСКЯХНнНїУнЗСЙ (ФнСжЯн) ШСЗТ 1987дЪг -гд Гнд КНСЯжЗї -гд еРЗ ЗбШСнЮ Ебм ЗбгФЗб(КМЗе (ГжТжнМж(ГжТжнМж)Ъд ЕРдЯ(гбЭЗК (УЯжЭнбП(ЗНЦСеЗ нЗ (МнгнГжСЗЮ ИШЗЮЙ ЗбЗЖКгЗдедЗ ГнеЗ ЗбЮЗЖПИЗбШИЪГнд УнЦЪ Яб гЗ нНКЗМ ббЗОКИЗБїУдРеИ бЬ(ГжТжнМж) нЗ СМЗббПнЯц ТЗЖСФЯСЗр бЯцФЯСЗрКИПнд гНИШЙбЗЎ ЩддКЯ УКЯжднд жЗбПн</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Niљta ne moћeљ da uradiљ.On je moj zarobljenik.Mora da postoji naиin...Иekajte!Uzmite mene umesto njega.- Tebe?Ti bi se zamenila s njim?Bel, nemoj!Ne znaљ љta radiљ!Ako bih, da li biste njega pustili?Da. Ali moraљ da obeжaљ da жeљovde da ostaneљ zauvek.Izaрite na svetlo.Ne, Bel!Neжu ti to dozvoliti!Imate moju reи.- Dogovoreno!Ne, Bel, posluљaj me.Ja sam star. Ja sam se naћiveo.Иekajte! - Bel!- Иekajte!Ne! Molim Vas, poљteditemi kжerku.Ona viљe nije tvoja briga!Odvedi ga u selo.Pustite me napolje!Molim Vas!Pustite me napolje.Molim Vas.Gospodaru?- Љta je?Poљto жe devojka da ћivikod nas priliиno dugo,mislio sam da biste mogli da jojponudite udobniju sobu.A s druge strane, moћda i ne.Niste mi dopustilini da se pozdravimo.Nikada ga viљe neжu videti.Nismo se ni pozdravili.- Odveљжu te u tvoju sobu.Moju sobu? Mislila sam...Hoжeљ da ostaneљ u kuli?- Ne.</se>
  </para>
  <para id="12">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Who does she think she is? That girlhas tangled with the wrong man.- No one says no to Gaston!- Darn right!Dismissed! Rejected!Publicly humiliated!Why, it's morethan I can bear.- More beer?- What for? Nothing helps.- I'm disgraced.- Who, you? Never!Gaston, you've got topull yourself together.Gosh, it disturbs meto see you, GastonLooking soDown in the dumpsEvery guy here'dlove to be you, GastonEven when takingyour lumpsThere's no man in townas admired as youYou're everyone'sfavourite guyEveryone's awedand inspired by youAnd it's not very hardTo see whyNo one'sSlick as GastonNo one's quick as GastonNo one's neck's asin credibly thick as GastonFor there's no man in townHalf as manlyPerfectA pure paragonYou can ask anyTom, Dick or StanleyAnd they'll tell you whose teamthey prefer to be onNo one'sBeen like Gastona kingpin like GastonNo one's got a swell cleftin his chin like GastonAs a specimenyes, I'm intimidatingMy, what a guythat GastonGive 5 hurrahsGive 12 hip -hipsGaston is the bestand the rest is all dripsNo oneFights like GastonDo uses lights like GastonIn a wrestling matchnobody bites like GastonFor there's no oneas burly and bra wny</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">гЯКИеНУдЗрЎ ГНЦСК бЯц гбЗИУ МПнПЙ...СГнК ГдФЯСЗрж НЮнИКЯКСЯКнеЗ Эн ЗбЪнЗПЙГдЗ Эн жСШЙ ЯИнСЙ Ъбм гЗ ГЩд...ГдЗнМИ Гд ГЪКРС бЯцеППждн ИШСПн гд ЗбЪгб Ед бг ГКНПЛ...жбЗЎ бЗедЗЯ ПСУ КЪбгКе МнПЗреж Где бЗ нМИ Гд КбЮн ИЗббжг Ъбм ЫнСЯ  ИОШГ ЗСКЯИКеНУдЗрбУК Гжб гжЩЭЙ ИенЖЙ ЕХбЗНнЙКЮЪ Эн НИ УМндХПЮнднбг неКг ГИПЗржбж НКм ИЮПС ИУнШЭнг КЭЯСїИЗбГОШЗБЯЗд ЪбнЯ Гд КЭЪбеЗбнУ ЯгЗ ЭЪбКбЮП ПгСК НнЗКеЗбЗ нжМП гЗ ИнПЯ ЗбВдеРЗ ЫнС ХНнНбЮП ГНИИКеЗХНнНїГнд (ГжТжнМж)їЪбм ИЪП дХЭ гнб КЮСнИЗрМнП</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Recite joj neљto.Nadam se da жe ti se svideti ovde.Dvorac je sada tvoj dom. Moћeљ daideљ svuda. Osim u zapadno krilo.Љta je u zapadnom krilu?- Zabranjeno je!Ako ti neљto bude trebalo,moje sluge жe te posluћiti.Veиera.Pozovite je na veиeru.Pridruћiжeљ mi se na veиeri.To nije zahtev!Љta ona umiљlja ko je? Ta devojkase igra s pogreљnim muљkarcem!Niko Gastonu ne govori "ne"!- Tako je.Odbaиen, odbijen,javno poniћen!To ne mogu da podnesem.Joљ piva?- Иemu? Niљta ne pomaћe.Osramoжen sam.- Ko, ti? Nikada!Gaston, moraљ da se pribereљ.Teљko mi pada da te vidimtako potiљtenog.Svako bi od nas hteo dabude na tvom mestu...иak i kad si u nevolji.Nikome u gradu setoliko ne diveTi si najomiljeniji momak!Svi su oduљevljenii inspirisani tobomI nije teљkoshvatiti zaљto.Niko nijezgodan ko Gaston,niti brz ko Gastonniko nema tako debeo vrat kao on.</se>
  </para>
  <para id="13">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">- Not a bit of him scraggly or scrawny- That's right!And every last in chofme'scovered with hair- No one hits like Gaston- Matches wits like GastonIn a spitting matchnobody spits like GastonI'm especially good at expectorating- Ptooey!- Ten points for GastonWhen I was a ladlate four dozen eggsEvery morningto help me get largeAnd now that I'm grownI eat five dozen eggsSo I'm roughly the sizeOf a bargeNo oneShoots like GastonMakes those beauts like GastonShoots like GastonMakes those beauts like GastonThen goes tromping a roundwearing boots like GastonI use antlers in allOf my decoratingMy, what a guyGaston- Help! Someone help me!- Maurice?Please! Please, I need your help.He's got her-- He's got herlocked in the dungeon!- Who?- Belle. We must go.Not-- Not a minute to lose.Whoa! Slow down, Maurice.Who's got Bellelocked in a dungeon?A beast!A horrible, monstrous beast!- Is it a big beast?- Huge!- With a long, ugly snout?- Hideously ugly!- And sharp, cruel fangs?- Yes, yes! Will you help me?All right, old man.We'll help you out.You will? Oh, thank you,thank you, thank you!You will? Oh, thank you,thank you, thank you!Crazy old Maurice.He's always goodfor a laugh.Crazy old Maurice, hmm?Crazy old Maurice. Hmm.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">ж КЭМС ГНФЗЖн ИЗбгЯЗд ЯбеїгЗРЗ ИЪПїбЗ нгЯдЯ Гд ЗбСНнбГдУнКїЕд ЮКбКднУКИЮм гЪнГдЗ ИГгЗд едЗГдК УМнд едЗбЯд бЗТбК ГКдЭУЕд ОСМК..ж бж ОШжЙУКдЮШЪ ГдЭЗУнКдЩСнд Ебншу...ЯгЗ бж ЯдК ФнШЗдЗрКСЯК ЪЗЖбКнГУдЗднГКдЗжб гОПС ЗбИнСЯжУнК ШжЗб ЗбнжгЭЮШ бГЦнЪ Гбг жМжПн ЗбгГУЗжнбнУ бПнЯц ЭЯСЙ Ъг гССК ИегЗ гССК Иеї(ЗбГгС бЗ нОХЯ нЗ (КнСЗдУЕнЗЯц(ЮУг ФСШЙ (ИбЗЯЭжКгСНИЗр(ЮУг ФСШЙ (ИбЗЯЭжК(гСНИЗрЎ ЗУгн (ЭнСжднЯЗ ПжджЭЗдГСнПЯг Гд КСУбжЗ УнЗСЙ ббгдТбИдеЗнЙ ШСнЮ ЗбгдЗСЙ ИГУСЪ жЮКВУЭ нЗ УнПКнГККХбнд ббЕИбЗЫ Ъд МСнгЙїдЪгЗСКЯИКеЗ СЖнУЙ ЗбжбЗнЗК ЗбгКНПЙЗСУбжЗ ЗбУнЗСЙВУЭ нЗ УнПнбЗ ГЩд Где нгЯддн еРЗедЗЯ ГЪХЗИЗУгЪ...КНКЗМ бгКОХХЎ НУдЗрї бУККНКЗМ ГНПЗрнЪСЭ гЗ нЭЪббнУК бПн ЗОКнЗСЗК гКЪППЙ нЗ ПЯКжСнПн ИКбЯ ЗбЛбЗМЙ гдР УЗЪЗКж ЗбГдУМЙ КгжКУнПнЎ бЗ нгЯддн еРЗЪдПн нП жЗНПЙ ЭЮШбЯд нгЯдднГд ГЫСТеЗ ИЪдЮЯЮИб Гд КХб ббИЗИж ЗбВд Ед бг нЯд еРЗ ПЗЭЪЗр ЯЗЭнЗр бЯГСм Гд бПнЯ ТжМЙ едЗИЗУг ЯеРЗЭн гЮЗШЪЙ ЯеРебд КжМП ХЪжИЙ ИЗбЪЛжС ЪбмУнПЙ (МжПЗК)Ў ХНнНїНУдЗрбЗ ГЪПЯ ИФЖеРе ЮХЙ НнЗКннМИ Гд ГЪШнЯ гОПСЗреб ГИПж ИеРЗ ЗбЫИЗБї</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Savrљen, pravi uzor.Pitaj bilo kogaI reжi жe ti na иijojbi strani voleli da budu.Niko nijekao Gaston,pravi frajer kao on.Niko nema rupicuna bradi kao on.Ja sam pravi primerakmuљkarcaUh, kakav frajerje taj Gaston!Pet puta ura!Gaston je najbolji,svi ostali su slabiжi.Niko se...ne tuиe kao Gaston,ne gasi svetlo kao on...U rvanju nikone grize ko Gaston.Jer niko nijetako krupan i miљiжav.Kao љto vidite,imam miљiжa na pretek.On nije zakrћljaoni koљtunjav. -Tako je!I sav sam prekriven dlakama!Niko ne udara kao Gaston.- I ne uzvraжa kao on.Kad se pljuje,niko ne pljuje kao on.Posebno sam dobaru gaрanju10 poena za Gastona!Kada sam bio detejeo sam 50 jajasvakog jutra, da porastem.A sada jedem 60 jajai velik sam ko bizon.Nikone puca kao Gaston,ni ne pogaрa kao on.A onda se razmeжeu иizmama kao Gaston.Rogove drћim kao ukrase!Kakav frajerje taj Gaston.</se>
  </para>
  <para id="14">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">- A dangerous pastime- I knowBut that wacky old cootis Belle's fatherAnd his sanity 'sonly so -soNow, the wheels in my headhave been turningSince I looked atthat loony old manSee, I promised myselfI'd be married to BelleSee, I promised myselfI'd be married to BelleAnd right nowI'm evolving a plan- If I--- Yes?- Then we--- No, would she?- Guess!- Now I get it!- Let's go!- Let's go!No onePlots like GastonTakes cheap shots like GastonPlans to persecute harmlessCrack pots like GastonSo his marriagewe so on will be celebratingMy, what a guyGastonWill no one help me?- Who is it?- Mrs Potts, dear.I thought you might likea spot of tea.But you're--You're a--- Oh! Careful.- This is impossible!I know it is,but here we are .I told you she was pretty, Mama,didn't I?All right, Chip, now, that'll do.Slowly now.- Don't spill.- Thank you.Wanna see medo a trick?- Chip!- Oops, sorry.That was a very brave thingyou did, my dear.- We all think so.- But I've lost my father...my dreams, everything.Cheer up, child.It'll turn out all right in the end.You'll see.Oh, listen to me...</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">нМИ Гд ГЮШЪ бНгЗр гнКЗрбЗ нгЯд Гд нКНгб ГНП ФнЖЗр ЯеРЗПжд гОПСГдЗ бУК ЯГн ГНПЯЗдК (ФжЗнКТС) ФСЯЙ ЗбУИЗЯЙЗбКн ХдЪК ЗбгСНЗЦЗбРн ЗУКОПге (УЯжЭнбП) ббОСжМ гд ТдТЗдКегЭЯ (Гбнд) ЯЗд ЗбгдЗУИЯбе едЗХНнНїгРеб"СЗнИ КФЗдУ жжПТ"ГедЗЯ гЯЗд ИЗбгЮЗШЪЙ нНгб еРЗ ЗбЗУгїЗСУб гд нИНЛ ИеРЗЕПЗСЙ ЗбУМжд КИНЛ Ъд гОТд(Эн (ГжТжнМжГнеЗ ЗбЮЗЖПЗбгПнС нЮжбГд (УЯжЭнбП) бПне ЕнМЗСИЗбжНПЙ 164бЗТЗб ЭЪЗбЗрбПндЗ ЦИЗШ ИЗбФЗСЪ ЗбЛЗгдж ЗбЛЗбЛЎ ж ЗбТЮЗЮЕд ЯЗджЗ едЗЯ ГнеЗ ЗбЮЗЖПЭЮП ГгУЯдЗ ИегдЦнЮ Ъбнег ЗбНХЗС ж ИЪПеЗЕд КНСЯ ГНПегУдЮКбеНЗЦСГнеЗ ЗбЦЗИШеРе ЪгбнКн ГдЗ нЗ РЯнКСЗМЪЗЫбЮжЗ ЗбИЗИбг нХбжЗ бФЖ ИЪП Ъд еРЗ ЗбгЯЗдїИбмЎ бг нКжХбжЗ бФЖбЗ нжМП гЯЗд ИеРЗ ЗбЗУг Эн ЗбИбЗП ЯбеЗжбЗ Гн ИбП ГОСменЗ ИдЗ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Molim vas! Pomozite mi!Zarobio je.Zakljuиao je u tamnicu!Koga?|- Bel.Moramo da krenemo!Ne иaseжi иasa.Polako, Moris.Ko je zatvorio Belu tamnicu?Zver.Straљna, monstruozna zver!Je l' velika?- Ogromna!Sa ogromnom ruћnom njuљkom?- Uћasno ruћnom.I oљtrih zuba?- Da, da! Hoжete li mi pomoжi?Dobro, starиe,pomoжi жemo ti.Hoжete?Hvala, hvala, hvala!Stari, ludi Moris.Uvek dobar za sprdnju.Stari ludi Moris, ha?Stari ludi Moris.Lefu, bojim seda sam razmiљljao...Opasna razonoda.- Znam.Ali taj stari ludak jeBelin otac.A priseban je tek, tek.Toиkiжi mi se u glavi okreжu,otkada sam video togludog starca.Obeжao sam sebi da жuoћeniti Beli sada razraрujem plan.Ako ja...- Da?Onda жemo.- Ne, da li bi ona?Pa, pogaрaj.- Sad kapiram!Idemo.Nikone smiљlja planovekao Gaston.Ne zadaje niskeudarce ko on.Uskoro жemo proslavitinjegovo venиanje.Kakav je frajertaj Gaston.</se>
  </para>
  <para id="15">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">- Chip?- Bye!Well, now, what shall wedress you in for dinner?Oh, let's see what I gotin my drawers .Oh, how embarrassing!Ahem.Ah, here we are!You'll look ravishingin this one!That's very kind of you,but I'm not going to dinner.Ah, but you must!Ahem, ahem, ahem, ahem, ahem.Dinner is served.What's taking so long?I told her to come down.- Why isn't she here yet?- Oh, try to be patient, sir.The girl has lost her fatherand her freedom all in one day .Master, have you thoughtthat perhaps...this girl could be the oneto break the spell?Of course I have !I'm not a fool.Good!So, you fall in love with her...she falls in love with you,and poof!The spell is bro ken.We'll be human again by midnight.Oh, it's not that easy, Lumiere .These things take time.But the rose has alreadybegun to wilt.Oh, it's no use.She's so beautiful and I'm--Well, look at me!Oh, you must help herto see past all that.I don't know how .Well, you can start bymaking yourself more presentable.Straighten up.Try to act like a gentleman.Ah, yes. When she comes in,give her a dashing, debonair smile.Come, come.Show me the smile.- But don't frighten the poor girl.- Impress her with your rapier wit.But be gentle.- Shower her with compliments.- But be sincere .And above all,you must control your temper!Here she is!Good evening.Well, where is she?Who? Oh, ha ha ha!The girl, yes. The girl.Well, actually,she's in the process of- -</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">жбЗ ЯбгЙГнеЗ ЗбЦЗИШбЗ ФЖеРЗ ЗбЭКм РЯнЕде бнУ гЯЗдЗрИб ЗУгГгЪЯ ЗбУМб ЗбгПднїдЪгГСнП ЕНХЗЖнЙ ЗбИбЗПгдР ГЮПг гЗ нгЯдедЗЯ гд УнСЗдЗЗУКгС ИЗбНЭСУдРеИ ббМНнг нЗ СЭЗЮГЮУг ИЗббе ГддЗ УдРеИ ббМНнгУЗЪПжднГдК СМб гСнЦ НЮЗрГКЪбг РбЯїЪг КИНЛїнМИ Гд дРеИ ббгЮЗИСЭн ЗбГХб ЯЗд нЭКСЦ ИеРеГд КЯжд гбЗИУ бн ж (бндЯ) бгПЙ ГУИжЪбЯд ГЩдЯг КНКЗМжд гУЗЪПЙгЛбдЗ КгЗгЗр...бРЗГдК КЭЪб еРЗ ЭЮШбШнИЙ ЮбИЯ нЗ (ЭнФ)ї(еРЗ ХНнН нЗ (МждЗбЮбИГдК КРЯС еРЗХНнНїКИЗр нЗ СМбеРЗ ЦнЮЯгЗ ЮбКнМИ Гд дден ПжСдЗ ЯУМдЗБж дХИН гПднндМгнбеРЗ ЗбУСжЗб ЮХнС МПЗрГбЗ КЩдїЗЮШЪ ЮПгнЯГдК ИЗСЪ Эн еРЗ</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Ko je?- Gospoрa Pots.Mislim da bi tiprijao иaj.Ali, Vi ste...Vi ste...Paћljivo!- Ovo je nemoguжe!Da, znam.Ali eto nas!Nisam li ti rekao da jelepa, mama?Dobro, Иip. To je dovoljno.Polako.Nemoj da prospeљ.- Hvala.Da ti pokaћem jedan trik?Иip!- O, izvinite.To je bilo jako hrabro, duљo.Svi tako mislimo.- Ali izgubila sam oca...snove, sve.Razvedri se, dete.Sve жe to na kraju ispasti dobro.Videжeљ.Oh, ja se raspriиala,a veиera treba da se postavi.Иip!- Zdravo!Љta жeљ obuжiza veиeru?Da vidimo љta sveima unutra!Kakva sramota!A to je to!Izgledaжeљ zanosno u ovoj.Vrlo ste ljubazni,ali ja ne idem na veиeru.Ali, moraљ!Veиera je posluћena.Zaљto je joљ nema?Rekao sam joj da siрe.Zaљto je nema?!- Budite strpljivi, gospodine.Devojka je ostala i bez ocai slobode.Gospodaru, jeste li razmiљljalida bi ova devojka moglada skine иini?Naravno da jesam!Nisam budala.Dobro.Vi se zaljubite u nju...a ona u Vas i puf!Иini su skinute!Do ponoжi, biжemo ponovo ljudi.Za takve stvari trebavremena.Ali ruћa je veж poиela da vene!Nema svrhe.Ona je tako lepa, a ja sam...Pogledajte me!</se>
  </para>
  <para id="16">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Uh, she's not coming.What!Oh, dear. Your Grace!Your Eminence!Let's not be hasty !- I thought I told youto come down to dinner!- I'm not hungry.You'll come out or I'll-- I'll--I'll break down the door!Master, I could be wrong,but that may not be...the best way to winthe girl's affections.Please attemptto be a gentleman.But she is being so difficult.Gently, gently.- Will you come down to dinner?- No!Suave, genteel.It would give megreat pleasure...if you wouldjoin me for dinner.And we say please.- Please.- No, thank you.- You can't stay in there forever!- Yes, I can.Fine! Then go aheadand starve !If she doesn't eat with me,then she doesn't eat at all!Oh, dear. That didn'tgo very well at all, did it?Lumiere, stand watchat the door...and inform me at onceif there is the slightest change.You can count on me,mon capitaine.Well, we might as wellgo downstairs and start cleaning up.I ask nicely, but she re fuses.Wh-Wh-What--What does she want me to do, beg?Show me the girl.But the master's really not so badonce you get to know him.- Why don't you give him a chance ?- I don't want to get to know him.I don't want to haveanything to do with him.I don't want to haveanything to do with him.I'm just fooling myself.She'll never see meas anything...but a monster.</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">ГКЭегжд ЮХПнїЕд ГСПК гбЗИУ гКджЪЙ"ЭЗРеИ бгКМС "КЗСМнК (бндЯ)гЗРЗ бПндЗїдЮжПЎ МжЗТЗК УЭСИШЗЮЗК еЗКЭ гПЭжЪЙ гЮПгЗрГСКФн СнЗд)ї)еб СГнК ЗУгнїЭнднЗУ гЗЯбндКжЯ)ї)ж еРеїгЭЗКнН ббУнЗСЙ ЗбКн КдКЩСдЗЪбм ИЪП гЖКн нЗСПЙ гд едЗдНд ЗбЗЛдЗд Гг дНд ЗбОгУЙїдНд ЗбЗЛдЗдГнЪбгждїбнУ ИЪПнЗ СЭЗЮнжМП ГНП едЗЯнЗ СЭЗЮнМИ Гд дРеИЯнЭ ЪСЭї</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Ne znam kako.Za poиetak, sredite se malo.Ispravite se.Budite dћentlmen.Kada doрe, uputite joj jedanoиaravajuжi osmeh.Hajde, pokaћite mi osmeh.Ali nemojte da plaљite devojku.Oиarajte je oљtroumnoљжu.Ali budite neћni.Uputite joj komplimente.Ali iznad svega...- Kontroliљite svoju narav!Evo je!Dobro veиe.Gde je ona?Gde je ona?Devojka? Pa...Zapravo ona je u toku...S obzirom na okolnosti...Neжe doжi.Љta?Vaљa Visosti!Vaљa Eminencijo!Ne ћurimo!Rekao sam ti da siрeљ na veиeru.- Nisam gladna.Izaрi ili жu, provalitivrata!Gospodaru, moћda greљim,ali to nije...najbolji naиin da jeosvojite.Pokuљajte da budetedћentlmen.Ali ona je tako teљka!Neћno, neћno!Hoжeљ li siжi na veиeru?- Ne.Polako, neћno.Bilo bi mi veliko zadovoljstvo...da mi se pridruћiљ.Rekli bismo i 'molim te'.Molim te.- Ne, hvala.Ne moћeљ ostati tamo zauvek!- Mogu.Dobro!Onda crkni od gladi!Ako neжe da jede sa mnom,onda neжe jesti uopљte.Ovo je loљ poиetak. Zar ne?</se>
  </para>
  <para id="17">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">- Oh, no.- Oh, yes.- Oh, no.- Oh, yes, yes, yes!I've been burnt by you before.Zut alors!She has emerged!Come on, Chip. Into the cupboardwith your brothers and sisters .But I'm not sleepy .- Yes, you are .- No, I'm not.I work and I slave all day long,and for what?A culinary masterpiecegone to waste!Oh, stop your grousing.It's been a long night for all of us.Well, if you ask me,she was just being stubborn!After all, he did say please.But if the masterdoesn't learn to control that temper,he'll never break the--Splendid to see youout and about, mademoiselle.I am Cogsworth,head of the household.- This is Lumiere.- En chante, cherie.If there's-- stop that--anything we-- please-- can do...to make your staymore comfortable--- I am a little hungry.- You are ?Hear that?She's hungry!Stoke the fire. Break out the silver.Wake the china.Remember whatthe master said.Oh, pishtosh! I'm not aboutto let the poor child go hungry.All right, fine. Glass of water,crust of bread and then--Cogsworth,I am surprised at you!She's not a prisoner.She's our guest!We must make her feel welcome here .Right this way, mademoiselle.Well, keep it down.If the master finds out about this,it will be our necks .Of course, of course.But what is dinnerwithout a little music?Music?It is with deepest prideand greatest pleasure...that we welcome you tonight.And nowwe invite you to relax.And nowwe invite you to relax.Let us pull up a chairas the dining room proudly presents...</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">гПднждГдЗ ВУЭГКЪСЭ Яг ЗбУЗЪЙїбЗЎ ВУЭбЗ нгЯддн Гд ГОСМУнЮКбжддн Ед СГжЗ жМенГдК гОШЖНЗбгЗ нСжд жМеЯУндКен ЗбГгС Ябе(нгЯдЯ ЗУКЪЗПЙ НнЗКЯ нЗ (КнСЗдУГеРЗ жЪПїГЪПЯгСНИЗрЭнСжднЯЗ)Ў еРЗ ГдЗ)бЮП ОСМдЗНгПЗр ббе Ъбм УбЗгКЯСГнК ЗбГОИЗСнМИ Гд КжЮЭ еРЗГСнПЯ Гд КУбг дЭУЯгЗРЗї(жМПК (УКнПгЗд(ГдЗ гЪе ЗбВд нЗ (бндЯЕде НнУнКг КИСЖКЯЗПОбжЗ(УКнПгЗд)гЗРЗ КЮХПнд ИГдЯ жМПК (УКнПгЗд)їКнСЗдУ)Ў енЗ ИдЗ)гУЗБ ЗбОнС(ЭнСжднЯЗ)ЗбФСШЙ едЗГСнПЯ Гд КИЮм гЯЗдЯУнПКн -бЗ ГСнП Гд ГОУСЯ -УнПКнЎ ГЫбЮн ЗбУгЗЪЙгЗРЗї(УнП (УКнПгЗдКСЗМЪ ббОбЭ(ЭнСжднЯЗ)(ЭнСжднЯЗ)нЗ Ебен(ЭнСжднЯЗ)</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">i odmah me obavestiako doрe i do promene.Raиunajte na mene,moj kapetane.Bolje da krenemo doleda raspremimo.Lepo je pitam ali ona odbija!Љta ona hoжe, da je molim?Pokaћi mi devojku.Gospodar nije tako loљkada ga bolje upoznaљ.Pruћi mu priliku.- Ne ћelim da ga upoznam!Ne ћelim da imam niљta sa njim!Samo se zavaravam.Ona жe u meni uvek videti...samo иudoviљte.Nema nade.O, ne.- O, da.O, ne.O.da, da, da!Veж sam se opekla o tebe!Oh, moj Boћe!Izaљla je!Иip, idi u kredenac sa braжomi sestrama.Ali, ne spava mi se.Spava.- Ne, ne spava.Radim i crnиim иitavdan i љta imam od toga?Kulinarsko remek-delo je propalo!Nemoj da zvocaљ.Ovo je bila duga noж za sve nas.Ako mene pitaљ,ona je tvrdoglava!Ipak ju je zamolio.Ako gospodar ne nauиi da kontroliљenarav, neжe nikada skinuti...Divno je videti Vas!Ja sam Kogsvort,љef domaжinstva.</se>
  </para>
  <para id="18">
    <se lang="alb" variant_id="0">Be our guestBe our guestPut our service to the testTie your napkin 'round your neck, cherieand we pro vide the restSoup dujourHot hors d'oeuvresWhy, we only live to serveTry the grey stufflt's deliciousDon 't believe meAsk the dishesThey can singThey can danceAfter all, missthis is FranceAnd a dinner hereis never second bestGo on, unfold your men uTake a glance and thenyou'll be our guestOui, our guestBe our guestBeef ragout, cheese so ufflePie and pudding en flambeWe'll prepare and serve with flaira culinary cabaretYou're alone and you're scaredbut the banquet's all preparedNo one's gloomyor complainingWhile the flatware 's entertainingWe tell jokes, I do trickswith my fellow candlesticksUnd it's all inperfect tasteThat you can betCome on and lift your glassYou've won your own free passTo be our guestIf you're stressedlt's fine diningwe suggestBe our guest, be our guestBe our guestLife is so unnervingFor a servant who's not servingHe's not whole withouta soul to wait up onGet off!Ah, those good old dayswhen we were useful- Huh?- Suddenly those good old days are gone- Oh!- Ten years we've been rustingNeeding so much morethan dustingNeeding exerciseA chance to use our skillsMost days we justlay a round the castleFlabby, fat and lazyYou walked in and upsy-daisy</se>
    <se lang="ara" variant_id="1">нКг КНжнбеЗ ЕбндЗеРе ГСЦ ЭнПСЗбнЙГдУнКїж ИЗбдУИЙ ббЪИКЯ ЗбХЫнСЙ едЗКг гХЗПСКеЗГУКОИСдЗ ЯнЭ ГКнК Ие Ебм едЗїГНЦСКе гЪнбгЗРЗїбГНгн дЭУнеРЗ УИИ жМжПдЗ едЗГдУнКїЭн ГЮб гд нжгЭЮПК ЗбФСШЙ ГЛСег...Эн КНЮнЮ гЗ нУгм ЗбВддЪгЎ еРЗ МнПКжб ЗбГгжС ИдЭУЯНУдЗрї(ЕПСЙ ЗбУМжд бЗТЗбК КгУН (ГжТжнМжбЯд ЗбСМЗб ЗОКЭжЗ КгЗгЗр(бУК жЗЛЮЗр гд еРЗ нЗ УнП (ГнЭТбЗ ГЪСЭ УС ЛЮКЯ ЗбФПнПЙ еРеЯгЗ бж Гд еДбЗБ ЗбСМЗбКСЯжЗ ОСнШЙ бОШ УнСегЭн ЗбжЗЮЪ еРЗ гЗ ЭЪбжЗ ИЗбЦИШУЯжЭнбП) СУг Яб ФЖ Ъбм МУПе)</se>
    <se lang="bos" variant_id="2">Moћemo li... Prestani.iљta da uиinimo... Molim te.da Vam boravak bude prijatniji.Malo sam gladna.- Zar?Иuste li?Gladna je!Potpalite vatru, probudite pribor.Setite se љta je gospodar rekao.Gluposti, neжu da dozvolimda jadno dete gladuje.Dobro. Иaљu vode,koru hleba i...Kogsvort, iznenaрujeљ me.Ona nije zarobljenik,nego goљжa!Mora se oseжati dobrodoљlom.Ovuda, gospoрice.Tiho.Ako gospodar sazna za ovo,gotovi smo.Naravno, naravno.Ali љta jeveиera bez malo muzike?Muzike?S velikim ponosom i zadovoljstvom...ћelimo Vam dobrodoљlicu.A sada se opustite,Dozvolite da Vam privuиemo stolicu,Dok Vam ponosno predstavljamoVaљu veиeru.Budite naљa goљжa,isprobajte naљu uslugu.Zaveћite salvetu oko vrata,a ostalo prepustite nama.Supa, topla predjela.Mi ћivimo samo da sluћimo.Probajte ovo sivo, izvrsno je.Ne verujete meni?Pitajte posuрe!Oni pevaju, oni pleљu,Gospoрice ovo je Francuska.A veиere su ovde najbolje.Hajde, otvorite jelovnik,Bacite pogled a ondabudite naљa goљжa.Da, budite naљa goљжa.Goveрi ragu, sufle od sira,flambirana pita i puding.Spremiжemo i posluћitiu kulinarskom kabareu.Sami ste i uplaљeni,ali banket je veж spremanNiko nije smrknut, niti se ћali</se>
  </para>
</body>
</html>